<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
<other>BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE DE FRANCE 

3 7531 05638706 2 </other>









<title>(No. 22, 1766.) 

CATALOGUE 

OF THE 

GENUINE COLLECTION 

O F 

. 

Coins and Medals, 

Various Antiquities, Fossils, and 

other Curiosities, 

Together with 

The remaining Copper-Plates, fome 

Manuscripts, Prints and Drawings, 

Of the late Revd. and Learned 

. 

William Stukeky, M.D. 

Fellow of the College of Physici a ns, 

and of the 

Royal and Antiquary Societies, 

Decease©; • 

Which will be fold by Auction, 

By S AMU EL PATE R SON, 

At EJfex Houfe in Effex Streetin the Strand, 

On Thursday and Friday, the 15th and 16th of 

May, 1766 ; 

To begin each Day exaflly at Twelve o&apos;Clock. </title>


<preface>II. No Perfon is to advance lefs than 6d. under 

One Pound, above One Pound is, above Five 

Pounds 5s. 

III. Every Purchafer is fo pay down 5 s. in 

the Pound, in Part of Payment, and to give in 

his Name and Place of Abode, if required. 

IV. The Lots are to be removed, with all 

Faults, at the Expence of the Buyers, within 
Three Days after the Sale is ended, and the 
Remainder of the Purchafe Money to be then; 
paid i in Default of which, the Depofit is to 

become forfeited, the Lots refold, and.the De 

ficiencies, if any, are to be made good by the 

firft Purchafers. </preface>




<unit>A 3 

10 Sundry 

m 


[ 4 ] 

Sundry ammonitae, echinitse, bivalves, Sec. 

Ditto, ditto, and fundry impreffions of vegetable* 
12 Ditto, ditto 
Ditto, ditto 
14 Ditto, ditto 
15 A large bivalve, a concha Veneris, 6 other bivalves, an 
oyfter, a roafs of oyilers, a &lt;arge cochlites, a bclem-
nite with its alveolus in Hone. and io others 

16 Forty-four fpecimens of poijrfad marbles and agates, 

and 2 large recent echini 

A ftudy of 124 marbles 

j8 A tea eejnipage of the&quot;SSWn ferpeiffine flone, contain-* 

ing 4 cups, 4 faucers, a tea pot, a fugar-diffi and co 

ver, 2 canifters and a falver 

19 A large ammonite, cut, and a large mafs of uibularia 

20 TwO plumb .piidding Hones, and a large foffil bo.ne 
Sundry fruits, feeds, modes, corals, fea fans, &amp;c. 




» 

CAB I N E T S, kc. 

Phi-


Philcfepbical and Mathematical hftruments, he. 

57 Sundry philofophical and mathematical inftruments 

58 Twomicrofcopes, 2 telefcopes, a brafs ring dial, and 4 
pocket compas 

59 A pocket cafe of inftruments,and fundry others 

60 A tide machine with a glafs (hade, and a brafs dial 

61 A day clock&gt; made by Dr. Cumberland, Bifhop ofPettr* 

borough 

6z A box of carpenter&apos;s, engraver&apos;s and other tools 

62*A theodolite 

• • 

» .* KivXH 

g 

4 I 1 £ . t \ 

. 

K 4 

X i. 

Stained Glafs. &apos; 1 

• 

;• 

,+ioY &apos;io m 

\ ri/id f Vvi *i 

63 A large box of old ftained glafs A 
64 Ditto 

&gt; 

6f Ditto t&apos; 

&lt; 

« 

&apos; 

66 Ditto 
67 Several large pieces ofditto,heads, coats of arms, broken 

« 

hiftories. Sic. 

0 

68 A fun dial, by J. Langton, of Stamford, 1719, •very ncat i 

in a wainfeot frame 

.3ml6l4 r 1 ,Vr,r&gt; «n:stnl; i:u. &apos;3 to a:..;. ;&gt;&gt; 

Various Antiquities. 

69 An Antediluvian hammer, fundry Druids beads, &amp;c. 
70 Sundry Egyptian and Roman antiquities 
ofv 

-

Veftiges of Roman pavement, brick, Roman and Etruf» 

5 -1 

can wares. Sec. 

72 Two Roman marbles, with inferiptions, a Roman tile, 

w -and 4 antique image tiles 

^3. Two Roman jugs, and 2 ditto urns with bones,-one of 
which from Ncrfclk 

*}//•» 74 A model of Stonehenge, in wood, by Dr. Siukelty 

/ r 75 A Roman hypocauft, a Roman pipe, or aquaeduct, an 

* 

Egyptian Ibis, and other antiquities 

76 Six Roman lamps, and 3 lachrymaries 

77 Ditto, ditto 
78 A 




^3 A Roman bafon and plate, a ditto difh, and a fine Etrufi* 

can vaf« 
-»--« •&quot;* 

79 A brafs Cerberus, antique 

80 A fmall bronze of Venus, ditto of Hercules and 2 Idols 
S-i Two alabafter figures, broke, 3 pieces of oldTpOrc-dain, 

and other odd Matters 

82 ABritilh fword, a ditto fpear head, the umbo of the 

Ihield, a broken urn, and a ditto glafs vafe, dug up 

with the Skeleton in a &apos;Tumulus at Chateris, in the ifle of 
Ely, with a drawing of the fame by Dr. Stukeley,-
A Britilh bridle, found with the old Britrfh King, dug 
up on the top of Silbury Hill, with a drawing of ditto by 

ditto 
83 Eight celts 
Sundry old keys, knives, &amp;c. 

85 An antique enamell&apos;d fhrine, with the print, *y. Tii-* &gt; 

lof. Tranfa SI. No. 49O. 
i-

, 

86 An old enamell&apos;d branch and a pair of antique fnuffersf 

rom Cropland Abbey, and an old brafs candlellick 

 §7 An old iron crofs, a fmall lead ditto, a fmall brafs ditto, 
a ditto crucifix, a reliquary, and other odd matters 
88 A fmall filver philigree crofs, a fmall inlaid ditto. Our 
Lady of Loretto, and a fmall filver image 
An agate rofary, a red bead ditto, a wood bead, ditto, 

and a ring rofary 
Eight antique feals, and 3 rings 
91 Eight ditto, 2 intaglias, a fmall enamel, and a ditto 
magnet, fet in filver 

Seven painted wood cards, or devifes, with infcriptions -

in old Englifh poefie 

-----

93 Several packs of cards of the earliefi make 
94 A reading glafs in tortoifelhell, filver mounted 

95 A convex glafs, a blue glafs cup, a piece of chryfial, 

and a brafs fcrew prefs 

A brafs incenfe pot, a double Alphabet of Greek 
characters, cut in brafs, and about a pound of 

quickfilver 
An Ecce Homo upon copper and a (ketch of an Altar 

piece framed and glased 

\ 

.. 

v 

Prints 


Second 



2 

«_-r 

5^* 

-

2 

c? S*&lt; 

&gt;&apos; S?/ 

&lt;r ,&lt;*&quot; 

-

^S&apos; / 2 2 

/ * s?* .. 

sz? ^, 

&quot; ^-&gt; &gt; 

^&lt;? 

~/+?-

-v 

r-

C^-&apos;&apos; 

«-



f &gt;0 ] 

*5 Brett&apos;on, Corcyra, Neapolis Diofeuria, Naxus, Chius iz 

z6 Ant&apos;oehuf Tryphon, Ptolomy, Phillip, Agrippa, and 
ether kings 
zz 
27 

Batlu.no, &apos;very rare, and a Jewilh coin 

z 

28 Aotiochus S&apos;tJonior, with Phoenician chara&amp;ers, fine, 

* 

and 1 of Antioch with ditto ; a fine Spanifh Lceita, 

and 1 more of Spain 
-

4 
29 One Cleopatra, 1 Samaritan, 3 modern Jewilh calls, 

a medallion of Aarelius, and 9 more 
-

14 

Silver Roman Denarii. 

TMperial from Auguftus to Sept. Severus 
ioz 



Jl Confular&apos;of feveral familie 

, 

tad&apos;y preferred 

33 

3Z Acilia. ./Emilia, Aquilia, Antiliia, Antonia, Carifia, 
Claudia, Fonteja. Julia, Junia, Lutatia, Marcia, 
Navia, P-ociaa, Sevilia and Tituria 
-

25 

Julius f, Auguf&apos;us i, Tiberius 1, Caligula (rev. Au* 

guRu*) 

Claudius (rev. Agrippina) t, Nero, 

Gaiba Otho, Vitellius, Vefpafiar., Titus and Do-
mitian 

iz 

Julius 1, Anthony 1, Lepidus &lt; 

3 

pempey t, Julius t, Auguftus 1, Gaiba z, Otho 1, 

Vitellius 1 

7 

Auguftus, with different rev^rfes, fome very rare 

15 

Julius 1. Auguftus 3, Tiberius 1, Nero 1, Gaiba t f 

Otho 1, Vitellius 1, Vefpafian and Titjis 17, Do-

mitiati 13 
39 

Nerva, Trajan, Hadrian, Sabina, Antoninus and 
Aurelius, Fauftina 

71 

./Elius 1, Did. julianuj i, Pertinax t, Verus 1, and 

E4-more 

--

18 

Trajan to Sept. Severus, in fine prejerajation 

13 

41 Gaiba, Vitellius, Nerva, ./Elius Crifpina, Barb. Or-
biana, Macrinus, Mariniania, and 6 more 

14 

42 Severus u, Julia Severi4, Caracalla 9, Geta 4, Elaga-
balus 3, Julia Mammea4, Alex. Severus 8, Maxi-

minus z 
40 
43 Gordianus Pius, dfferent re&lt;vtrfes 

25 

44 Phillip *0, Phi lip jun 3, Otacilia 1, Traj. Decius 4, 
Meff, Decius », Etiufcilla 2, Volufian 3, Treb, 

Gallus 4 

28 

45 Valetianp, Gallier.us 1 5, Valerian jun 3, Saloninus i, 

and Pofthumus 12 

~-* 

. ---

34 

6 Confiantius 3, julianus 4, Valens 1, Valentinian 4, 
Tl.codofius t, Arcadius t, Honorius J, Juflinian j 16 
47 Dioclefian, Maximianus, Prebus, &amp;c.fine 

c 

ifi 

Greek 


Vf 

c^_? / 

&lt;-^-/X -

.*&apos;^&gt;&apos; ~s&apos; !_:&lt;&apos;--

C^&quot; 

&apos; -

«?x / X 

U^^^&quot; 

*^^2&apos; ~^&apos;X&apos; -*&gt;&quot;&apos; 

L?&apos;-^ 


f 


Greek Silver. 

ANE tetradrachm of Thafus, 1 of Athene, 4 of 

^Rhodes (different fizes) and i more --g 

Rhodes 1, Thalus i, Athens 1, and a tetradrachm of 

Lyfimachus 

--r 
4 

Phillip j, Alexander 1, Lyfimachus 1, Athens 1, and 

2 more 
-

-
6 

51 A fine tetradrachm of Seryphps, ditto of Rhodes 

* 

*51 An ancient and rude one of Phocea, and a King of 

Caria, very rare 

-

a 

52 Scipio 1, Pompey 1, Anthony 1, 1 of Ptolemy, and 

1 more falfe 

--

j 

Roman and Greek Gold. 

53 &apos;y&apos;Alentinian 1, Arcadius 1, Honorius 1 
-

3 

54 
Lyfimachus, very fine 

« 

j 

55 Ptolemy, Jmall and very rare 

.. 

• -

t 

Britifh Silver. 

56 &apos;J&apos;WO different, one of them large, both finely pre 

ferred 

t 

57 Five fmall ditto or Gallic, on one of them antono 

£ 

Britifh Gold. 

58 QNE with the horfe, the rev. plain, another ditto, 

the gold and work very bad 

-

2 

59 Two ditto, ftruck on both fides 

-&gt;2 

bo Three ditto fraaller, and finely preferred 
--

3 

Britifh Brafs. 

61 Four different, and a barbarous coin in lead 

Englifh Copper. 

61 &apos;J&apos;Radefmen, jettons, &amp;c. 

--

188 
63 

A medal of Sir Ifaac Newton 

--

1 

64 A medal of King George II, and the royal family, by 

Croker 

---

-

« 

i 

65 ..... 

the Duke of Montague, by Daflier -

1 

Engii&apos;u 


( II ) 

Saxon, Englifli and Foreign Silver, 

&apos;B&apos;Oreign coins and medals, and two Engljfh, wt. 

Engliih money of feveral kings from Henry to 

Charles lid, from the crown to the farthing, 

wt, 

Oils i» jfithelftan l, Edred 1, and the Confeflbr in 

his chair t 

•--

Henry the IldYJ&apos;jnny, Henry Vi blanc, Edward Vi&apos;s 

threepence, and 6 more 

70 A fine medal of James the lid and his Queen, rev. 

Uaufraga Referta 

» 

FINIS. 


S&apos;*&apos;&apos; &apos; y yJ 

•s sy </unit>







































<back>J </back>



</text>
</tei>