<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">



<title>ROBERT *9-8 








y*&apos;p 

CATALOGUE 

Of the Genuine, Curious, and Wellkrown 

COLLEGT|©U 

Ciy &apos; 

&apos; 

-/ 

o * 

(2 :l.F 1) -j 

Greek, Roman, &apos;end btlier 

C O I NS and M E D A L S, 

O F 

Mr. Thom ah Grainger* 

7 
Late in the Pofleffion of 

Jofeph Tolfon Lockyer, Efq; 

Deccafea; 

\ 

Which will be fold by Auction, 

By Mr. Langford and Son, 

At their Houfe in the Great Piazza, Cozent Garden 

» 

On JVednefday the 26th of this Inftant February 1766, 

and the four following Days (Sunday excepted.) 

mu 

The /aid Colleftion may be viewed on Monday the z\tb, anj 

till the &apos;Time of Sale, which will begin each Day punctually 

at Twelve o&apos;Clock. 

Catalogues to be had gratis on the Days of Viewing, 

at Mr. Langford&apos;s aforefaid. </title>


<preface>Conditions of SALE. 

Jl, fTp H E higheft Bidder is to be the Buyers 

1 

and if any Difpute fhall arife between 
any two or more Bidders, the Lot fo difputed fhall 

be put up again, and refold. 
idly, No Perfon to advance lefs than 6d. under 

a Pound 

•, 

above a Pound u. above Five Pounds, 

2S. 6d. and fo on in Proportion. 

3dlv, The Purchafers are to give in their Names 
and Places of Abode, and to pay down Five Shillings 

in the Pound (if required) in Part of Payment of 

the Purchafe Money -r 
in Default of which, the 

Lot or Lots fo purchafed, to be put up again 

and refold. 

4-thly, The Lots fhall be fetched away with 

all Faults, at the Buyer&apos;s Expence, within three 

Days after the Sale i and the Remainder of the 

Purchafe Money absolutely paid on or before 

the Delivery. 

Laftly, Upon Failure of complying with the above 

Conditions, the Money fo depofited in Part of Pay 

ment, fhall be forfeited 

•, 

the Lots uncleared within 

the three Days aforefaid, fhall be refold, by publick 

or private Sale, and the Deficiency (if any) together 

with the Charges attending fuch Refale, fhall be made 

good by the Defaulters at this Sale. </preface>



<unit>/. 

//: 

/ 70 

/ / 

&apos; 

/ / 

/c 

/-/ 

Roman Confular Denarii. 

y^Uuria 1, Acilia 1, ^Emilia 2, Antonia 15, Cor 

nelia 2 

Emilia 1, Antonia 6, C&lt;efia i, Cecilia 1, Calidia 1, 

Caiifia 1, Cordia 1, Cornelia 1, Domitia 2, Eg-

ratuleia, Furia t, Julia 1, Junia 1, Licinia 1 

28 ^Emilia 1, Calidia 1, Carifia 1, Caffia 1, Cipiae 1, 

Cornelia&apos;!, Cordia 1, Domitia 2, Fabia 1, Far-

fuela i, Flaminia 1, Kofidia i, Julia 1, Junia 1, 

Marcia 1, Sergia 1, Tituria «, Vibia 1, In-

certa 2 
« 

-

29 Emilia 1, Cipiae f, Cordia f, Fabia i, Furia z t 
Julia 1, Liciniae 1, Marcia 1, Muffidia i, Naevia 1, 

Plaetoria 1, Pompeia 1, Porcia 2, Scribonia i, 
Sentia i, Servilia 1, Sulpitia 1, Vibia 1, In-

certa 1 

-

-. 
30 Cordia 1, Furia 2, Junia 2, Minucia 1, Muffidia 2, 
Papia 1, Plautia 1, Pompeia 1, Poltumia 3, Pro-

^cilia i, Rubria I, Rofcia 1, Sulpitia i, Veturia 1, 

and 2 more 

Roman Imperial Denarii. 

* « 

3! &quot;pOmpey 1, Juba 1, Nerva 

^Elius 1, Fauftina i, 

Valen 1, mag. mod. 

Julius (remfe Anthony) 1, Auguftus 1, Tiberius r, 

Caligula (reverfe Claudius) 1, Claudius, Nero 1, 

Galba, Oiho, Vitellius 1, Vefpafian 1, Titus 1, 
Domitian t 
Augudus, with different reveries 

-

34. Aueudus 1, Tiberius i, Claudius (rev. Agrippina) 

Nero 1, Galba 1, Othoi, Vitellius 1, Vefpafian 1, 

Titus i, Domitian 

1 

Vitellius i, Y&apos;efpafian 1, Titus 1, Domitian 1, Nerva 

1, Trajaff 1, Hadrian 1, Sabina r, .TElius 1, An 

toninas i, Fauftina fen. 1, Aurelius 1, Faurtina 

jun. 1, Veras 1, Lucilla 1, Commcdus 1, Crif-

pina 1 

36 Vitellius 1, Nerva 1, Vefpafian 4, Titus 3, Domitian 
4, Trajan 6, Hadrian 6 

. 

Vefpafian 3, Titus 3, Domitian 3, Nerva 1, Trajan 3, 

Hadrian 3, Antoninus 4 

... 

Vefpafian 4, Titus 3, Domitian 6&apos;, Trajan 7 
Trajan 9, Hadrian 7, Sabina 1, Antoninus 3 

40 Sabina 1, Antoninus 8, Fauftina 4, Verus i 

4« 


m 

w 

+&gt; 


2 

C 6 ) 

Nero, rev. Germanicus, and 1 of Aurelius, both mag. 

mod. rare 

-

Ariftotie 1, Artimefia 1, ard 7 more cafts and coun 

terfeits 

A Jewifh fhekel, and an atuela 

-

A piece with a head, iev, a temple, baibarous cha 
racters, and 1 in brai&apos;s, with di&apos;to 

2 

75 Six ancient pieces in lead, a broken gold Britifh, and 

3 more 

-

8 

Auguftus of the Papyrian family, and 20 more colony 

coins 

From Auguftus to Honorius 

--

50 

SI 

// 

11 Tlj&apos;Oreign coins of bad filver or billon 
j 2 
Foreign coins of moft countries, good filver, wt. 15 
oz. 7 dwr 

*ia Ditto, wr. i 2 oz. i6dvvt. 

13 Eaft India rupees, fanams, &amp;c. wt. 3 oz. 
I 4 A 10 dollar piece of Julius Duke of Brunfwick, wt. 9 
oz. 8 dwt. 
I 5 Five curious fiege pieces 

16 Thirty old Swedifh coins, of different Kings 
17 Forty Arabics, Perfic and Turkilh coins 

30 

40 
18 Three 

M 

sO 


/o 

/ 

y / 

( 7 ) 

»8 Three old fquare rupees, an half Siam tical, and 6 

more Eaft Indian 

19 Twelve half rupees with the figns of the zodiac, and z 

whole ditto 

-*-* 

-

&lt; 

zo Two very curious pieces of japan, a fquare rupee and 

one more 

. 

21 Five German religious medals 
Foreign medals and jettons, wt. 4 oz. 4 dwt. 

Three dutch medals, and a porter&apos;s ticket, 402. 5 dwt, 
24 A medal of Charles Guifavus, and 3 more 
A Dutch medal on the truce 1609; a jetton on Eliza 
beth&apos;s affixing the Dutch, an ancient jetton 1492, 

and 

1 

more. wt. 3 oz 9 dwt. 

26 Sixtus V, Innocent X, Alexander VII, and 1 more, 

wt. 2 oz. 1 4 dwt. 
A modern Hebrew medal, a perpetual almanack, and 
one of Queen Margaret, wt. 1 oz. to dwt. 
A fine talifman, and an engraved plate of Henry IVch. 

and his Queen, by Simon de Pafs 

--

Englifh Medals. 

29 I4 Lizabeth, Quid nos fine te, and one ftruck in Holland 

L * 1586, a jetton of Lord Buckhurft, and 1 of 

Lord Traquair 

--
30 Elizabeth Queen of Bohemia, daughter of James I 

*30 Charles I, one with his head by Briot, the other 

on horfeback, reverie of both a view of the city of 

London, and j more 

31 Small medals at;d jettons, of ditto 

« 

Oliver Cromwell, reverfe. Pax Quaritur Bello 

Col. John Lilburne, finely preserv&apos;d (Vert. pi. xxii. 1. A.) 

34 Lord treafurer Southampton (Vert, pl.xxix) 

EarlofEffex, gilt, finely prefier^&apos;d [Ven. pi. x let. c.) 

36 A common wealth&apos;s man, name unknown, by Simon, 
fine bull 

-

37 Archbilhop Laud, fine 

-

38 Charles 1 Id. in his coronation robes, reverfe, Jupiter 

deltroying the Titans, by Bowers, gilt, finely pre 
fers d, and n try rare 

-

• pro Talibut Aufis, fine, wt. 2 07. 1 9 dwlj&gt; 

Favente Deo, fine, wt. 2 oz. 9 dwt. 

Redeant Conmtnia. Flandres, wt. 2 oz. 17 dwt, 
a i&apos;fuadrato ad Line am Re£iam, wt. 1 oz. 9 dwt, 

Diffufius in Orbe Britannus, and a fine one 

39 


4&lt; 

42 


on Charles XL receiving the order of the garter 

44 Sir Edmundbury Godfrey, Equo Credite fiucri 
*44 One on the rtftoration, and a jetton of Sir Robert Pye 

10 

H 

4 

3 
11 

t 

1 

1 

1 

1 

45 Jame* 


V* 

N 

/. // 
/X 

/ # 

&apos; 

X: 

/£ 

. 

7 2 

/ //-

/-O* 

&apos; &apos;f 
l 

// 

(s; 

45 James lid. and his Queen, Naufraga Reperta, finely 

preferred 

46 Archbifhop Sandcroft 1, Earl of Shaftelbury 
-

47 James lid. reverfe, his Queen j a lilver angel, and 4 

jettons of the Chevalier 

48 William Illd. reverfe, reftitutore, wt. 3 oz. 8 dwt. 

49 

two jettons of ditto and Mary, and 8 

more 

5°• Pretium caufa Laboris-Ne totus abfu-

matur 

51 Anne, Nova Palladium Trejo, fine, wt. 3 oz. 5 dwt. 

52 

Pugna Eque/lris-Entirely Englijb, and thus united 
invincible, wt. 2 oz. 10 dwt. 
53 ---Sine Clade Victor-Tornaco Expugnato, &amp;c.-Com-
pofijis Verierantur Arm, wt. 2 OZ 9 dwt. 
-
54 

Montibus, &amp;c. Captio -Gallio ad Aldenard 

Victor. -Entirety Englijb, wt. 2 oz. 8 dwt. -

5 5 

Piet as Augufia 

56 George I. Adventus Regis, wt. 3 oz, 8 dwt. 

57 Princefs Sophia and the Emprefs Matilda, fine, wt. 

4 oz. 4 dwt. 

58 The coronation medals of James I, Charles I, Charles 

II, James If, William and Mary, Ann, George I, 

George and Queen Caroline, wt. 4 oz. 19 dwt. 

Britifh and Gallic Coins. 

59 ClX different, with head on one fide, and horfe on 

the other 

-

Ditto 
Ditto 
Ditto 

-* 

-

Ditto 

-

r 

Ditto 

-

Englifli, Scotch and Irifh. 

65 /&quot;&apos;•Harles I, Oxford half crown pieces of Briot, and » 

more 

?--
-

James I crown, teftoon of Edward VI, 3 pence ditto, 

and 2 more 

67 A penny of Alexander III, groat of David, and 2 

more 

68 A 40 (hilling piece of James II, and 5 more Scotch 

A Carlifle fhilling, 2 Pontefratt ditto, and the half 

crown of Newark 

* 

70 An Inchiquin crown, an Ormond fixpence, and 3 

more 

--

---

6 

1 

tes 

11 

3 

71 Charles 

VO 

VO 

*0 

vO 

vO 

sO 


( 9 ) 

Charles II, coronation medal at Skoon, a jetton of 

Mary, and i of the Chevalier 

3 

72 Two Irifh groats of Edward IV, a fine {hilling and 

groat of Elizabeth, and j of James I 

9 

73 One William the Conqueror, an half groat of Henry 
V I, a piece with ancient characters, and 4 more 

7 

74 A fatyiical medal on the reformation of William and 
Mary, a perpetual almanack, and 3 more 

75 A parcel of coins of feveral Kings, wt. 9 oz. iydwt. 

76 Ditto, wt. 7 oz. 19 dwt. 

Britifli Coins in Brafs, 

&quot;NJINE different, very rude 

78 

Eight ditto 
79 Ditto 
Nine ditto 

Englifh Copper Medals. 

81 A Medal of Charles the firft, 1 of Queen Mary, 2 of 
Anne, and 1 of George the firft 

5 

82 One of Mary, 
1 of Anne, 1 of the King and Queen of 

France, and 1 of Archbifhop Wake 

4 

83 One of Anne, 2 of George the firft. 4 jettons of the 
Chevalier, and 2 of William and Mary 

9 

84 One of Oliver, 1 of Mary, 1 of George the lid, 

1 of 
Caroline, and 1 of Prince Frederick 

5 

85 One of Charles I, 
1 of Mary, 2 of George I, and 

one of Sir Ifaac Newton 

5 

f. Two of Sir Ifaac Newton, and 1 of Archbifhop Wake 

3 

Queen Anne, 19 different 

19 

Town pieces and tradefmen 

--

83 

Irifh gun money, from the crown to the fixpence 

30 

Halfpence and farthings of different reigns 

--

75 
91 Jettons, coins, abbey pieces, &amp;c. 

1*6 
A large parcel of foreign coins 
----

415 1 

93 Englifh, Scotch, Irifh, plantation 

• 

88 

Ditto, tickets. &amp;c. 


[ to ] 

&lt;S5?&lt;35 

6&amp;m 

Third Day&apos;s Sale, Friday, Feb. 28. 

/ //, 

&apos;of 

/ /-

/-

/-

. 

/ 

y 

/3 

/ 

/ / 

/ 

SAXON. 

Lot 

1 

/^\FFA, with his head 

-

i 

z 

Offa, no head 
I 

3 Coelwulf 1, Burgred i, Eadred I 

-• -



4 Athelftan, with head 
1 ; ditto, no head, Ethelred 1, 
Edgar i 

--

4 

5 Ditto, ditto, ditto, ditto, 
4 

6 Ditto, ditto, ditto, Eadred 1 

4 

7 Ditto, ditto, ditto, 



8 Edwig 1, Eadred 1, Athelftan 1, Edw. the confeffor 2 

5 

9 Edgar, with head 

1 ; Ethelred 1, Edmund 1, Edward 
the Confeffor 2 

-. 

. 

5 

10 Edward the Martyr&apos; 1, Athelftan i, Ethelred I, 

Edward the Confeffor 1 
4 
11 Edwig 1, Athelftan 2, Edward the Confeffor 

1 

4 

12 Athelftan, reverfe, a church 1 ; Cnut 1 (blundered 
legend) Edward the Confeffor i 

3 

13 St. Petri 1, Incerti 1, Edward the Confeflor 1, (broke) 3 

14 Ethelred i, Ftreman tno Dyjhn, Athelftan 1, Hareld 1 

3 

. 

^15 Swefnerd Moneca, reverie, Dorobernia civitas, rare, 

Athelftan 1, Edward the Confeffor 1 

3 

ENGLISH. 

/ 

/. // 

/-

// 

// f 

// /f 

/ 

S&apos;. 

/a 

/ 

16 TX7llliam I and II, Conqueror 4, Rufus 3, different 

7 

17 

ditto 

7 

18 -

With the canopy, fine, and 

1 

with Paxs 

z 

19 Henry I penny, with the annulets, rare 

---

1 

20 

With pax, very rare 

I 

21 Stephen 1, Henry the Firft 1, Henry the I Id 



22 

Ditto, ditto 



23 

Ditto, ditto 

• 



24 Euftace, fon of Stephen, his penny, rare 

-1 

25 Stephen and Henry, very fine and rare 

-

1 

26 Henryll, penny, John halfpenny and penny 

-



27 Henry II, fine, Henry III, 5 pennies, different 



28 Henry III, 6 pennies, and 6 of Edward I and II, 

12 

29 Edward I and II pence, half pence and farthings 

30 -&apos; 

groat, very rare 

-&gt; 

I 

31 Edward 


31 Edward III, farthings, halfpence, pence, half groats, 

and groats 

Richard II, groat and halfpenny 

-

2 

33 Henry IV, V and VI groats, half groats, pence and 

half pence 

34 Edward IV groats, halfgroats, pence and half pence 

Richard III 2 groats, with the rofe and boar&apos;s head 

2 

36 Henry VII, full and fide faced groats, half groats, 

pence and half pence 

37 

Shilling, badly preferred 

-

1 



-• Shilling, fine and rare 

-

j 

Henry VIII groats, half groats, pence and halfpence 

Edward VI teftoons, different 

41 

with Timor, &amp;c. on the head, fide 

42 
counter ma.k&apos;d with a portcullis, &apos;very rare 



ditto, fine filver, rare 
Mary and P. z M. fhihing, fixpences and groats 
Elizabeth, from the crown to the two pence 

--

11 

46 

. 

milled (billing, fixpence, three pence, &amp;c. 

47 
hammer&apos;d (hillings, fixpences, groats, and 
three pences, two pence% pence and halfpence 

48 J ames I crown, half crown, (hilling, fixpence, two 

pence, pence and halfpence 

half crown, exurgat, fine and rare 


5°5 

&apos; 

52 





55 

5 6 

57 

58 

59 

Charles I xx (hillings, x (hillings, v (hillings, 11 (hil 

lings vi pence, xn pence, vi pence, iv pence, and 

hi pence, coined at Oxford 

ditto, and the 11 pence 

--

ditto, xx (hilling, x (hilling, v (hilling, 

xnd, vid and mid, ditto 

a x (hilling, and 2 (hillings coin&apos;d at Oxford, 
2 (hillings, and 2 fixpences, by Briot 
a crown and half crown, exurgat. and an 
half crown, 2 (hillings and 1 fixpence, Ebor. 
two crowns,&apos; e (hillings, 3 fixpences, 2 two-
pences, and 2 pence, Tower mint 
a rare (hilling, with type of the half crown, 

and a heavy fixpence 

a crown, half crown, (hilling, fixpence, half 

groat, penny and halfpenny 
-

-

one crown, 1 (hilling, 4 fixpences, one 
half groat, penny, and halfpenny 
the Oxfoid Ciown, finely preferred, and ex 

tremely rare 

*5 

2 

7 

9 

60 Oliver Cromwell, half crown and (hilling, finely pre 

fixed 

1 

2 

61 Ditto, crown, and half crown 

2 

62 Ditto, half crown 1656, very rare 
-

I 

B 2 

63 Charles 


/6 
/2 

/2 

/5. 

#: 

0 

) 

[ &gt;2 ] 

63 Charles II. 1 (hilling and 4 fixpences of his hammer&apos;d 

money, and 7 more from the penny to the groat 

it 

64 -

half crown, (hilling and fixpence, with 

out date or circle 

-



Milled Money. 

1 

65 rHarl es II. 1 crown, 3 (hilling, and 4 fmall pieces 

66 

1 

crown (rofe) half crown, (hilling (fea 

thers) and a fixpence 

--
--
67 Ditto 

•&apos; 1 

68 James lid. crown, half crown, (hilling and fixpence 

t&gt;9 

two half crowns, I (hilling, and 

1 

fixpence 

70 William and Mary, ditto, and the penny, twopence, 

threepence and groat 

71 William ill. crown, half crown, (hilling and fixpence 
jz 

half crown, (hilling and fixpence with 
feathers; fixpence with rofes, and a (hilling with 

the head on each fide 

73 Anne, crown, half crown, and (hilling with rofe and 

feathers; a fixpence without, and the 4 fmall 

pieces 

74 

crown, half crown, and fixpence with feathers, 
and a (hiding without 

---
73 

half crown, (hilling and fixpence (Vigo) another 
half crown, and 3 other (hillings 
76 George I. crown, half crown, and (hilling with rofe 

and feathers ; and fixpence, groat, twopence and 
penny 

-

---

77 

ditto, S. S. C. and a threepence 
-

78 

* 

(hilling of the WCC, 1 half crown, 2 fix 

pences, and 8 fmall from groat to a penny 

79 George II. (hilling and fixpence with feathers, 2 other 

(hillings, 6 fixpences, and 

1 

groat 

80 William and Mary half crown, 6 fhillings, t fixptnce, 

2 groats, z threepences, 3 twopences, and 5 pen 
nies of different reigns 

--










4 





4 






I Z 

II 

20 

Fourth Day&apos;s Sale, Saturday, Marchi. 

IRISH. 

Lot 

I T70UR ancient Irifh kings, finely preferred 



z J/ Henry Kid penny, 3 ditto of Edward I and II. 

and 1 halfpenny ditto 
--

5 

3 Edward 


[ &gt;3 3 

4 Edward IV, Villa de Trim 

/O. 

J3 

a groat and half groat, with 3 crowns 
groat, with large rofe 
half groat and penny, with the fun&apos;, rare 
groat, with fun on one fide and rofe on the 
other, unpublijbed 

-

* 
1 

groat. Dubline, 

1 with three crowns 

Henry VI. ditto 

another Drogheda, and 

/2 

/3 

n 

JO 

JO 

K J0 
&apos; 0 

1 

/ • 1 

Jv 

/II 

Henry VIII 4 groats, with ha, hi, hk &amp; hr 

11 Mary, groat and (hilling, rare 
Phillip and Mary, fixpence 1557, (hilling 1355 
13 Elizabeth, bafe fhiiling and fixpence, with her head 



fine (hilling and groat, with 3 crowns 1561 

.. 

bafe fixpence with arms, half penny and 

penny in copper 

----

16 James I 3 (hillings and 2 nxpences different 

SCOTCH. 

jy HpWO pennies of William I, 2 of Alexander H, 2 

X of Alexander III, and 

1 

of John Baliol 
18 Robert, 1 penny, 2 half groa:s, and 2 groats; one 

penny, 2 half groats, and 2 groats of Davie II 

tg James 111 and IV 2 groats, 1 half groat, and a bafe 

penny ; and 3 groats of James V 
20 Mary&apos;s teftoons with her head crown&apos;d and not crown&apos;d 

z i 

ditto, not crown&apos;d, finely preferred 

---

22 

4 teftoons, and 3 half ditto, all different 

23 

z ditto, 

1 

with the head and countermatk&apos;d, and 

4 pieces bafe filver 

24 Mary and Henry 3 of different 30, 20 and ic (hilling * 

piece 

25 James VI 2 xxx (hiking pieces 1569 and 1571, and 2 

bafe pieces 
26 

xxx, xx, and x (hilling pieces 

-

27 -
xl, xxx, xx, and x (hillings, compleat 

2 3 -

noble, 10 (hilling, &amp;c. and the crown and 

twopence of Charles I, with his father&apos;s type 
29 Charles I. 1 crown, 2 half crowns, 2 (hillings, and 7 

more pieces 

30 Charles II double rna&apos;k, mark, and half mark ; and 

the dollar, half, quarter, 1-eighth, 1-fixteenth, 
compleat 

31 James VII 40 and-20 (hillings; William 40, 20, 10, 

and 5 (hillings; William and Mary, 60 and 10 
fhillii g&apos; ; and Anne i; (hillings 

32 The coronation medal of Charles I» that of Charles II 

at Scoon, and 2 jettons of Mary 

«---

* \ 

4 

3 

4 

10 

4 
Coins 


\ 

s 

V 

H ) 

Jlruck in France, 
in the Eaft and 

Weft Indies.. 

/ 

&apos;/ //&apos; J^Dward the Black Prince&apos;s gold coin called a chaife, 

•very fin e, and extremely rare (Ant. Soc. pi N°3 ) 
34 Henry VI falule. finely preferved, and very rare 

, j --blanc, rare 

. J a 36 Elizabeth&apos;s Portcullis crown, ha&apos;f crown, (hilling and 

fixpence for the Eaft India trade, fine and rare 
Common Wealth. New England twopence, 2 three 
pences, : fixpence, and 3 (hillings of Maffachufet&apos;s 

Bay ; and a fhilling with n e 

^38 Charles II, a Maryland fhilling, fixpence, and groat of 

Lord Baltimore&apos;s, rare 

Siege Pieces. 

39 r^Rmond money from tlie twopence to the crown, a 

• 

hne fee 

--

40 Inchiquin crown, half crown, {hilling, fixpence, and 
groat, rare 

* 

41 Crowh with Vs on both fic.es, and half crown with 

ns vid, rare; Corkxn&amp;vt, rare 

-

41 Newark xxx, xn, ix and vid 

-

43 Pontefratt {hillings, 4 d.fferent 

2 

/ 

44 Carlifle in (hillings, and t fhilling, very rare 

-/0 4 5 Scaiborough 

1 

{hilling, extremely rare 

-

46 Ditto 1 {hilling and vi pence, extremely rare 
47 Ditto 11 {billing^, and vi pence (View Silver Coin, 
pi. it;. No. 10.) extremely rat e 
48 Ditto v {hillings (ibid. No. 11.) extremely rare 

Patterns and Proofs in Silver. 

49 TTEnry VIII fitting on his throne, with London 

J &quot; L wrote at bottom, ah unic 

50 Edward VI, fi &apos;e faced, ufually called his half crown, 

very rare 

---
51 A rofe crowned between f r, inferibed e d g Rofa fine 

fipjna, iecerfe. Hurra Londinenfis -Another in 

feribed Rofa fine /pina, reveife, Pro lege rege &amp; 

grege, both very rare, 

. 

52 Elizabeth, AJJliSloru^f con/ervatrix, and the pledge of a 

/ 

penny 

53 James 1, portcullis and 

1 r crowned -Charles I, rofe 

and thiftle between c r 

Another Fidei Defenfor, 
and 2 more, rare 
54 Charles 

N 

-f* 


2 

[ «5 1 

54 Charles I, two probably for xnd, one bare headed, the 

other crowned, reverfe, Aufficiis Rex Magne Tuis 

t 

by B ior, very rare 

-
-

, 

5 3 Charles I half crown, O Rex da Facilem curjem, and 

a groat with rofe over ini, by Briot, rare 

56 Comroor.wealth. Blor.deau&apos;s (hilling and fixpence, fine 
and rare 

57 

• -

his half crown, Truth and Peace i6jt, 

Petrus Blonde us Inventor Fecit 

58* 

* 

ditto, In the third Tear of Freedom by 
God&apos;s Bfjjing refiored 1651 

-

59 ---

Ramages fixpence, Truth and Peace 
(Vertue, pi. 13.) 

• 

60 

. 

ditto. Guarded voith Angels 1651 (ibid) 

61 Charles II. Magnolia Dei &amp; Magna Opera Domini, 

by Simon, rare 
-
62 
a fuppofed pattern for a farthing. Truth and 
Peace, re/erfe, the three pillars. Thus united in 

vincible, and a fisa&apos;l one with rofe and X 
63 The farthing token of Charles I, 3 different farthings 

of Charles II, 1 of William and Mary, and 2 of 

Anne 

-

-

64 Ifie of Man penny, and xxx of James II, gun money 

65 Jame3 1 crown, xxx, xn and vi, gun money 

66 A fine proof crown of Charles II, half crown of Geo, I. 

1 

(hilling of William 111, and 1 (hilling of Anne 

2 

2 

I 

I 

1 

( 

2 

2 

7 
2 

4 

4 

Patterns and Proofs in Gold. 

67 &apos;Ej&apos;Dward VI, a fine half fovereign, with the leafed 

J 

rofe on the reverfe, fine and rare (View of Gold 

Coin, pi. 3. No. 3.) 

1 

68 Charles I xx (hilling piece, inferibed, Florent Concordia 
Regno, very rare 

-

I 

69 Pontefrad liege piece, (ibid. pi. 6. No. n.) an unic, 

fine prejervation 
--

I 

70 Commonwealth, (hield of England on one fide, that of 

Ireland on the other, inferibed, Truth and Peace on 
both (ides and the edge, fine, and extreme rare 

1 

7? Charles II, a broad piece, by Simon 

-

1 

72 James II, a xxx, xn&apos;and vi of his gun money 

3 


Foreign Gold. 

Lot 

1 

TpOUR ducats of George I, Guftavas Adolphus, the 

JP Czarina, and the late Emperor 

-

4. 

2 A Flemifh fovereign, and 2 more, wt. 1 2 gr. 9 dwt. 

3 

3 One in commemoration of the reformation in Saxony, 
and an old piece of Holland 

-

2 

4 An Ealt Indian pagoda, 2 rupees, and 5 more . 

8 

5 A fquare piece of japang, and a coupang of ditto 

2 

6 A fine medal of Innocent XII. wt. 10 dwt. 17 gr. 

1 

Scotch 

V) 

W 

^ 



t 18 ] 

47 Elizabeth&apos;s two half fovereigns, milled 

-

48 
ryal, very fcarce 

-

49 James I, feeptered unit, and its half Ang. See. a thiftle 

crown and half crown 

---

ditto with Mag. Brit. 

ditto, with a border and loop, and counter-
5°5 

* 

52 
53 
54 

55 Charles Id&apos;s angel, xx (hilling, and x (hilling firuck at 

Oxford, and a x (hilling of the Commonwealth 

56 

• -

ml piece, xx (hilling, and x (hilling of 

the Oxford mint 

-

57 Commonwealth&apos;s xx (hilling, x (hillings, and v 

marked with the arms of Amllerdam 

double role ryal and fpur ryal 
x&gt;x (hilling, and xv (hilling pieces 
thiille crown and v (hillings 

(hil 

lings 

-

58 Oliver Cromwell&apos;s broad piece, fine and rare 

59 Charles lid&apos;s broad, half broad, and 2 five (hilling 

-
two guinea piece, fine 

-

61 William llld&apos;s five guinea piece, with elephant, fine 

Greek and Roman Gold, 

62 pHillip&apos;s gold drachm 

-



Alexander&apos;s ditto 

didrach, fine 
Opontium in Greece, a drachm 
66 Tiberius 

Gratian, Confiantius, and a quinarius of Juftinian 

68 A byzantine, what Emperor uncertain 

Britifli Gold. 

69 QNE with a horfe on the concave fide, the convex 

fide plain 

• 

&quot; 1 &quot; 

70 Two ditto llruck on both fide?, one of which filled with 

a fort of funs and crefcents 
71 One ditto with a horfeman, fine 

1 

*-

7a One fmall with cvn on one fide and a horfe, and a 
wheat ear on the other, with ca-mv, fine and 

Gallic 


( &gt;9 ) 

Gallic Gold. 

7 3 ONE infcribed dorestati fit, rev. haAelim?s, 

-one semelia coyc-eitard Me, and i more 

3 

74 One taroannaf, rev. vsca -another dalabe, rev. 

commilin, and 2 more 
--

---

4 

FINIS. 

f\VC 

VO 

VO 

(A 

o» 

o 


-&quot;-fjfcf -. -

.*rn XT/.T:3*ea LsdriV) i &apos;^^Q| £ 

Ĵit 

i I b~3 ,3M n T 3 -0^*3 AMpMlt 0.1.1 -

.VJ3 J3AJ 3 I. i 

-,..32/ .731 ,1A*KA04aY 9oO 

-.... 

--• 
atoon s bo.; .mail moo 

,*ry:Yf ft. : jnS 

--

t.&apos;.Cfl C ,73T&quot; 

I IrT f * « 

c?r.a xx 

--. 

( l.:.vT ;!•;* 3.. 1 -TJM/.6 .7*1 

&apos; 

? 

VXSVt 

V\tt t 0l3!AT .V31 ( M1J320&apos;.:U0 d i./uao 

.Vc.&apos; ,* ?. 

rtYYiiv: 

p 

01 

mijsl d:\-ft trr?1 f -r i &apos; ) ttl/T&quot; cS 

|. £ «M 

--• 

£?s gninrr.^ca 

rv;i r:. . • .j 

_ 

. 

;.i ,\ i 

xxi^xl; cl :Lro t&apos;Si.f ixwij 

&gt; 

v:&gt; 

, 

&gt; 

oA .&apos;&apos;n-y 

A (0 

trxvf^V.;* » v: 

; i&apos;• Vv. \ V 

. 

• &lt; 

&apos; 


mmmmm 






u </unit>






</text>
</tei>