<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">








<title>CATALOGUE 

O F 

A Moft Curious and Valuable CABINET 

O F 

ROMAN and Other MEDALS and COINS, 

In Gold, Silver, and Brass; 
The Property of a Gentleman lately arrived from 

ITALY: 

Among many equally rare, are, 

THE TWELVE CiESARS, 

In Gold, in the higheft Prefervation; 

A great Variety of 

Antique Marbles, neatly executed for forming Cabinets, Szc. 

ALSO, 

Some exceeding fin£ Antique Intaglios and Cameos fet in 

Rings, &amp;c. Bronzes, Models in Terra Cotta, matchklV 

Pieces of Antique Rock Chrystal, an Epergne, fe-
veral Lots of ufeful Plate, Jewels, he. Two magnifi 

cent Cabinets for Medals and Jewels, and Two ele 

gant Book-Cases, all richly inlaid. 

Which will be Sold by A U C T I O N, 
&apos; 

By W. BRISTOW, 

At the New Auction Room in Pall Mall, on Monday, 
Tuefday, and Wednefday, the 2d, 3d, and 4th of 

March, beginning precifely at Twelve o&apos;Clock. 

The Whole may be viewed on Friday the 27th, and to the 
Time of Sale (Sunday excepted) when Catalogues may be 

had at the Room ; and of W. Bristow, Rolls Buildings 

Fetter-Lane : Who fells by Commiflion, on the moft rca-

Ionable Terms, Eftates, Stocks in Trade, Furniture, Me 
dals, Books, Pi&amp;ures, Prints, &amp;c. or procures immediate 
Purchafers for them. </title>


<preface>Conditions of SALE. 

I. »r p HE higheft Bidder is the Buyer; and if any 

I Difpute arifes, the Lot to be put up again. 

II. That no Perfon advance lefs than Six-pence ; above 

a Pound, One Shilling; above Five Pounds, Two 

Shillings and Six-pence. 

III. The Buyer to give in his Name, Place of Abode, 

and pay Five Shillings in the Pound earneft (if de 

manded). 

IV. The Lots to be taken away with all Faults, at the 
Buyer&apos;s Expence; and the Remainder of the Pur-

chafe Money to be paid on the Delivery, otherwife 
the Money depofited is to be forfeited, and the Lors 
uncleared to be fold by Public or Private Sale, and 

the Deficiencies (if any) to be made good by the 

Firft Purchafers. 

V. The Lots will be delivered the Days of Sale, from 

Nine in the Morning till Seven in the Evening (the 
Time of Sale only excepted); and it is moft earneftly 

requefted the Buyers will be expeditious in taking 
away their Lots, as the Room mull be immediately 

cleared. 

!Thofe Gentlemen who cannot attend the Sale, may have 

their Ccmmiffionsfaithfully executed, by their moft 

Rolls Buildings, 

. 

Fetter lane. 

Obedient and devoted 

Humble Servant, 

W. BRISTOW. </preface>



<unit>(4) 

f Medallions of Didius Julianus, Commodus, Fauftinus, Sept; 

14 &lt; 

Severus, Gordianus, Trebonius Gallus, Probus, Gallienus, 
£ 

and Salonina 

-

-8 

15 jElianus, fmall brafs, very rare, and 1 Marius 

-2 

Silver Coins and Medals. 

Imperial 


Lot 

54 
55 

Imperial Silver Denarii, &amp;c. 

Fifty-eight Confularand Imperial Denarii, wt. 5 oz. 15 dwt. 

Pompey, revtrft, his two Sons, fine work. Scipio Afrit 

canus and Agripf^_ _ Pektinax 

Med. Mod. rev. Lib. Aug. 

t 

Julius Cjesar. Legions of&quot; Mare. Anthony. 11. m. vii. vm. 

xv. Augustus 5. Rex Juba Vespasianus 6. Domi-

TJANUS I, NERVA f. TbaJANUS 4. 

24 

Hadrianus 5. Antoninus 3. Faustina i. Marcus Au 
relius 4. Faustina juts* 4. Commodus 4. Cris-

PINA I 

22 

Sept. Severus 6. Julia Pia 3. Caracalla 7. Plautil-

LA I. GeTA 5 HeLIOCABALUS 3 

25 

Heliogabalus 4. Julia Paula t. Julia Maeta i. Max 
iminus 1. Puppienus plated I. Gordianus Pius i i. 
Phillippus Pater i I. Phillipus jun. 2. Otacilla 3 

-25 

Trajanus Decius 2. Hetruscilla 2. L. Herennius 4. 

TrEBONIANUS GaLLUS 2. VoLUSIANUS I. VaLERIA-
nus 4. Gallienus 2. Salonina 2. Saloninus Va-

LER1ANUS I 
-20 

Galienus half /ilvered 24. Salonina 2 

--26 

Claudius Gothicus 28 
-28 
Fifteen Greek filver Medals, among which are two Alexan 
der, and a beautiful one of Opuntas 
A fet of the Twelve Caesars in filver Denarii, in fine prt-

Jervation 

Marbles for Cabinets. 

A Series of fquare Samples of Marbles ufed in the antique, 

and fome in the modern Buildings of Rome, confiding of 
50 hard as Porphyry, 165 foft, and 24 of the Country 

of Barut; in all 239, of the Meafure of 4 Inches of the 

Roman Palmo, for a Cabinet 

Ditto of 42 hard, and 188 foft; in all 230, of the Mea 

fure of \\ Inches of the Roman Palmo 

Ditto of the fame Meafure of 35 hard, and 145 foft; in all 

180 

Models in Wax, framed and glazed. 

Cherries, French Beans, and an 
Artichoke 

Queen Caroline and the late King of Sweden, by Gro//^ 


-6 The Judgment of Paris, and Venus and Adonis 

57 Bacchus, Silenus, &amp;c. 

Hiftories, &amp;V. m Bronze, framed. 

A fine Head and 3 more 

-4 

Mars and Venus, Mercury and Io, a Group of Satyrs, and one 

more 

-4 
Judgment of Paris, Vulcan forging Mars&apos;s Armour, Mutius 

Scaevola, and 1 more 

-4 

Fourteen Seals, fome very ancient 

A Set of Diamond Weights and Scales, and an old Scale Box 
with Money Weights 
Four neat Miniatures painted on Vellum, framed and glazed 
Four Ditto 

Models, Bronzes, Chryjials, &amp;c. 

A fine Model in terra cotta of his late Majefty, as big as Life 

by Roubilliac 

A fine Model in terra cotta, of a Monument intended for Lord 

Shelburne, by Roubilliac 

Ditto 
A Buft as big as Life, in Plaifter, of Lord Ligonier 
Three Baffo Relievo Heads, in Plaifter, of Mr. Pope, Mr.Han-

del, Mrs Oldfield, and 5 Plaifters, framed and glazed 

A fmall Head in terra cotta of Lord Ligonier, by Roubilliac 
A large Cupid in Bronze, holding a Dolphin 

A Bronze Group of Two Cupids 

Two large Bronze Figures with Drapery 

Two Bronze Figures on Pedeftals of Roman Generals 
A fine Baflf. Relievo in Bronze, of a Bacchanalian, highly repaired 
Six fine large BafTo Relievo Bronzes of the Sufferings of our 

Saviour, framed, highly repaired 

Two Bronze Figures of a Satyr and a Venus on black Pedeflal 
A Bronze of Bacchus filling his Cup with Wine-
A large Bronze of the twaMen Wreftlers 
Ditto of Women Wreftlers 
Two Heads in Bronze of Mr. Pope and Mr. Handel 
Two Phantom Bronzes, Temptation of St. Anthony 

A Bronze Group of Silenus 
Two fmall Bronze Cupids, on black Pedeftals 

Two fmall Bronzes of a Horfe and a Bull 
A Bronze of a Gladiator, holding a Man&apos;s Head 

T wo neat fmall Cabinets for Jewels and Medals 

*% A 


Lot 

88 j 

?9 

9°9 

1 

921 

93 { 

9+ 

95 

( 7 ) 

A large matchlefs antique Chryftal Shell, with two Handles 

curioujly engraved 

An antique Chryftal Salver, with a gilt Foot 
An antique Chryftal Cup, with a Foot and z Handles 
An round antique Chryftal Salver, with a Foot 
An antique long Chryftal Drinking Glafs, and a curious 

Chryftal Spoon 
An old antique Copper enamelled Salver and Cover, by Julie 

Romano 

Two old antique Copper enamelled fquare Pictures, gilt frames 
Two fmall curious Amber Figures in Bell Glalfes 

End of the Firjl Day&apos;s Sale. 


23 | 

241 

2 5 

26 

A Miniature Pifture of a Celebrated Milanefe, by Raphaelimi 

the Jew 

Ditto df Ceres, by Signora Urban:, from the celebrated Bat-

toni 

Ditto of Angelica and Medoro of Ariofto 

Ditto of the Duchefs of Portfmouth, Favourite to Cha. II. 

Two Portraits on Copper 

Marbles for Cabinets. 

A Series of fquare Samples of Marbles ufed in the antique, 
and fome in the modern Buildings of Rome, confiding of 

37 hard as Porphyry, 137 foft, in all I74, of the mea 

sure of 5 Inches of the Roman Palmo, for a Cabinet 

Ditto of 5 Inches, hard 25, and foft no; in all 135 

Ditto of 4* Inches; in all 110 

Ditto a very large one, being of 13 Inches by 8, of the 

Roman Palmo ; the hard 25, and the foft 85, in all 110 

Antique engraved Onyxes, Cameos, Intaglios,&amp;c.fet in Rings. 

3 2 

33 

34 

3 5 

36 

37 

C An Onyx of a fine blue upon a black Ground, reprefenting 

| 

the Head of a Woman with a Cafque 
CAn Onyx of a finer blue, with the Emperor Adrian and Sa-

i bina joining Hands 

An Onyx with the Head of Minerva covered with a Cafque 
5 AnOnyx, with Meleager Handing before a Rock, upon which 

1 

is the Head of the wild Boar, and a Greyhound at his Feet 

An Onyx with a Greyhound catching a Hare 

An Onyx with the Head of a young Roman with an Infcription 
38 A 


lot 

38 

J 

39 

40 

4* 

4*&lt; 

very fine large Vermillion, or, as it is called in Italy, a 

Giacinto Guarnaccino, a Stone that undoubtedly is 

tll% Carbunculus, or the Pyropus of the Ancients. Venus 
ftfhing and catching little Cupids 

A Vermillion, with a Soldier relieving his Comrade leaning 

{ 
upon his Shield 

f A bright Cornelian, Achilles fitting on the GrouKl w tb his 

[ 

Cafque in his Hand. An Etrufcan Work 

A Cornelian, with the Head of Cybele.or of a Town 
j-A Cornelian reprefenting a Woman with the Caput Turritam, 

leaning on a miliary Stone, upon which is marked the 

Number lxxi 1. Before her fits a Man crowned with Reeds, 

to w&apos;hom a Boy prefents other Reeds. From the marked 
diftance the Woman may be luppofed Rome, and the 

leaning Divinity the Lacus Fucinus, from which came 

the Aqua Claudia to Rome 

A Cornelian, upon which is delicately engraved, an Eagle 

43 i fighting with a Dog, and under them a Hare concealed 

under a Grotto 
44 A Chalcedonian red coloured, Neoptolemus facrificing Poiixena 

\ A Sardonyx icarcely tranfparent, upon which is the Phrygia 

45 1 

fitting and mourning* and before her a Trophy. An 

p 

Etrufcan Work 

46 4 A Sardonyx of a deep colour, but tranfparent, Etrufcan Work 
t 
and reprefents a Soldier with his Spear and Parazonium 

\ A Sardonyx with a Horfe as kneeling, with an half Moon, a 

4jf Branch of a Palm-tree, and round it, C. Fufius Phi-

LOSTRATUS 

A Garnet very neat, wich a Man of the Baths having a Stri-
gil hanging from his fhoulders 
A red Jafper, with a Crane coming out of a Buccinum, a 

Dolphin, Sec. 
A red jafper, with a Fawn 
An Onyx, with a Bacchante: the Work appears modern 

A noble Cameo, with the Head of Ant icon us King of Syria, 

52 &lt; 

of a fine White, upon a Ground of a Sardonyx, and of 

Greek Workmanfhip 

C A Cameo, with the Bulto of a Venus coming out of the Sea, 

53 | 

0 f a fi ne white flelhy Colour, upon a Sardonican bottom 

^4 A large Cameo, with the Head of Anti nous 

55 Ditto of a dying Gladiator 
A Lady&apos;s Ring of a Vermillion, fet in the m-ddle, and round, 

with very fitke Rofes 

The Head of an Emperor fet in a remark dole Gold Ring, 

found in Leicellerlhire, 
* rj*ry curh.es 

Thirty Intaglios antique and modern 
-30 

EP 

$9 Litto 

48 \ 

49 

5°5 

1 

56 { 

57 

*3 


( IO ) 

JjOt 

59 
60 

*60 | 

6, | 

62 
63 
64 

65 

Thirty Intaglios antique and modern 

A Bird on a Green Jafper, and 

1 

more 
Young Hercules on a Cornelian, and a Chimaera on 
both fet 

A Temple with four Figures on a Jafper, Malk of a 
ditto, both fet 
The Head of Socrates on a coloured Onyx 
A fine Cat&apos;s Eye in Sardonyx. 
Vefpafian&apos;s Head on an Onyx, a Cameo 
A fine Head of Agrippina on Lapis lazuli 

-30 
-2 

a Jafper, 

-2 

Satyr on 

&gt;-2 

Plate, Watches, Jewels, &amp;c. 

81 

A Fifh Trowel 
82 Four pierced Salts and Glades, and a Milliard Pot 
83 A Pair of Sauce Boats 

84. 

A large Chafed Waiter 
85 A very elegant wrought Epergne 

86 A curious Defert, &amp;c. of Chinefe Enamel 

S2 A Blood 


(II) 

Lot 

87 
88 
89 

90 

9 1 

92 j 

93 
J 

941 

95 

961 

97 

98 { 

A Blood Stone Snuff Box mounted in Gold 
A Mocoa ditto 
A Lapis-lazuli Powder Box ditto 
An Inftrument Cafe, in a Pillar of Gold, in the Doric Tafte 
Two Onyxes fet in Gold enamell&apos;d Seals 
A fine large Clufter Diamond Ring, wt. 16 Grains, fet round 
with 12 Brilliants, wt. 10 Grains 

A pair of Ear-rings of two fquare Berillus Stones, commonly 
called Marine Water, with 10 Grains of Brilliants 
A Negro&apos;s Head in an oriental Agate, fet in Gold, with an 

engraved Onyx 

A Gold Watch (Guilloche) of Mr. Godin the Elder, at Paris 

An exceeding neat ditto, in a curious engraved Cafe, by 

Le Roy, Paris 

A Gold repeating ditto, Scbretner 
A curious Roman Infcription found at Silchefler, with the 

Brafs Frame that belongs to, and was found with it; *-

Defcribed in the Pbilo/ophical PranJactions, No. 474, et 

490. and by Dr. Stakeley in his Caraujius 

GOLD MEDALS. 

100 

IOI 

| Augustus divi f. c. cjesar aug. eques decurrens, &amp;c. 
| 

Tiberius. Figura fedens 
Tiberius Claudius. Corona quercea. s. p. r. ob. c. s 

Antonia augusta, ad. Figura flans cum hafla, et cornucn-

99 I Tiberius. Figura fedens 
Augustus divi f. c. c^esar aug Eques decurrens, &amp;c. 

1 

Nero. Caput juvenile, ad. font, max.tr. p.vi. cos. mi 

102^p . p. 
Vespasianus. ad vie. aug. 

t Nero. Caput juvenile, ad pont. max. tr. p. iii p. p. 

10 3 ^Vespasianus. ad. vie. aug. 

t Nero. ad. Augustus germanicus 
104^V espasianus. ad. judjea 
TNero. Caput Juvenile, ad. Figura militaris cum hafla con-
\ 

culcans fpolia, ex. s. c. &amp;c. 

1 5 j Nero. ad. salus 

Vespasianus. ad cos. iter. tr. pot. 

f Vespasianus. ad. Figura flans, cos. 111. pont. max. 

Domitianus. ad. Jmperator eques 

10 J Honorius. ad. victoria auggg 

LConstantinus Poconatus. ad, crux 


Lot 

( 12 ) 

Domitianus. ad. Imperator eques 

Theodosius 
Justinus 

Co nstantinus max. ad. Figura fedens cum ramis, ad pedes 
captivus et trophaeum. constantintana daphne 

Hadrianus. ad. Imperator eques. cos. hi 

Faustina minor, ad. venus 
Plac. Valentinianus 
Constantinus Pogonatus 

Marcus Aurelius, ad. Figura flans, felicitas auq. 

cos. Ill 

Faustina aug. minor, ad. Figura fedens pafcens ferpentem, 

SALUTI AUGUSTAE 

Honorius 

Flac. Valentinianus quin. 
Constantinus Copronymus 

Constantinus et Irene 
Michael etTheophilus 

Constantinus Pogonatus quin. 

A little Carthaginian 

End of the Second T)afs Sale. 


( r 3 ) 

9&lt; 

Lot 

-&gt; 

f Roman Coloniis. Auguftus, Corinth. Ditto in Vaillant non 

ex tans. Cajuget Lucius Cafario. Tib. Claud. Col. A. A. 
Patr. Nero, Col. Corinth. Ditto, non relata Vaillant. L. 
Verus, Col. L. Jul. Corinth. IJis Pharia deficit in Vaillant. 

&gt; 

J 

Ditto, altera deficient. Caracalla, Col. Pella. Alex. Severus, I 

Col. Iroad. Jul. Mammea, Col. Pella. Gallienus, Diana j 

non in Vaillant. Gordianus Pius, Col. Kar. 

--\}-A 
M. ALmilianus, Col. Vamincia, an. xu. middle Brafs 
An antique Medal, taken in a Mineralization of Iron, Lead, 

and Copper. A Chriftian modern Medal with the fame 

Ruft, or fine patina, of one of the moft antient found in 

the Fields near Rome 

5 Three Scriptorii Styli, 5 Brafs antient Keys, and fome other 

2 l Pieces of Brafs 

C A fmall Brafs Box ornamented, fit for ancient Balms; and a 

* l Weight of Black Stone 

S A Slate of Lapis Lazuli* ditto of Amethyft, and ditto of Ori-

ental Caftra Cart 

10 i 

//-

«•% 

Silver Confular Coins. 

*5 

16 

f l 7&lt; 

Forty-five Roman Confular Silver Denarii 

* 

&apos; 

^Emilia, Appia, Aquila, Baebia, Calpurnia, Coelia, Cippia, *» | Ĉocceia, 

Cornelia, Crepufia, Flaminia, Fouria, Fonteja, 

Hoffidia, Hoflilia z, Julia 3, Licinia, Lucretia, Martia2,e 

Memmia 2, Minutia z, Muflidia 2, Porcia 4, Pofthumia, f 

Pompeja, Rubria, Scribonia 2, Sergia, Servilia, Thoria, * 

* 

_ 

Titia 3, Tituria 2, Tullia, Vibia 2, incerta I 

-50 fAEmilia 

2, Afrania, Appia, Antonia, Atilia, Atilia the Head of 

Regulus, Calpurnia, Cecilia, Cippia, Crepufia, Cornelia, &apos; 

Fonteja, Hoftilia 2, Flaminia, Fouria, Julia 3, Junia, -* 
Lucilia, Memmia 2, Minacia, Minucia 2, Muflidia, Pa-

pia, 

Papiria, Pompeja, Pomponia Porcia 3, Rubria, Ser-\ \ 

via, Scribonia, Thoria, Tituria, Titia 3, Tullia, Vibia 2, ^încerta 

3. In all 
&quot;&quot;» 5°3 

&apos;• 

(a 

/A 0 

t 

* / (p 

Afelefl Series of Imperial Silver Denarii, in the highejl 

Prefervation. 

I* 

Quirinus, Ancus, Pompejus, Rev. Navis, Nassidius, 2 
ditto, Julius C.*sar, Cossutius Maridianus, ditto 

Buca, and 3 ditto 

v 

-10 

19 Lepidus 3, Marc. Antoninus 5 

-8 

%:/7&quot; h 

20 Marcus 


26L 

ot 

! t.q &gt;• io 

/&quot; ? &apos;24 

/ t. p &apos;&apos;0 

%ult • V 

&lt;L •!:«? 27 

/ .J*:0 28 j 

f../&lt;J:P ?9 J 

/ &lt;t,*ev&gt; 

V &apos;• /*&apos;•« 3 

/ * ft-6 33 

j? . /£*&lt;m 

. 

£&lt;-&apos; ^351 

•&apos;/ c&apos;J&apos;. «3 6 M 

/.*&gt;-* 

7 

j 

a 

&lt; 

a.. ^3s| 

2-4-oTo 

r/ • /.-£ 4°-
/ jyj&apos; h £&quot;t&apos;* 

/ &gt;. flL^O 4 2 _ 

/ *. / 

&quot;/•,.*-*4 
2&quot;2 * ^~45 

r 

/ &quot;/7^/f 

5 75-^7&apos; t 

•2~4 3 

/ /. 6 -49 j 

fpM 

Marcus Antoninus, and Cleopatra 

-. 1 

Marcus Ant. and L. Anton. 

*-1 

Aucustus, different renterfes 
-10 

Augustus, different renterfes 10, Tiberius, Quadriga, Sc 

2 ditto 

-j 3 

Caligula, plated. Corona civica ob C. Servat. 

-1 

Caligula, r. Agrippina 

-i 

Tib. Claud, r. Agrippina plated. Ditto. Corona Civica 
Nero, r. Clypeus Eqwestre Ordo, &amp;c. Ditto plated 
Agrippina &amp; 3 

-7 

Galba 3, Otho 1, Vitei.lius 3 

-7 

Vespasi/»nu3, r. Capita Titi &amp; Domitiani, and 11 others 

-12 

Vespasianus, Canfecratio. Ditto Quinarius, Sc 7 rfV//&lt;7. Titus, 

r. Judea. Ditto nttith the Quadriga, Sc 1 a&apos;/Z/o -12 

Titus, r. Quadriga. Ditto Confecr. Ditto Quinar. Sc 8 ditto II 
Julia Titi, r. Venus, £pV, 

Domitianus, different renterfes, and a Quinarius 

-&apos;12 

Domitianus,Quinarius. D/7/o.*&quot;Nerva 6, Trajanus6 14 

Trajanus, different and rare renterfes 

-1 5 

TraJanus, different renterfes. Pntto Greek, a Quinarius, iff 

Confecratio 

--

16 

art 1 an a and Ma tibia, rare 

Matidia, a mojl beautiful and highly preformed Medal, r. 3 

figures. Pietas Augujl. 

-1 
Hadrianus, 12, among nvhich area Congiarium, and other 

fine renterfes 

H adrianus, fame fine renterfes 

-15 

Hadrianus 6, Sabina 4, .Aslius Cjesar i, Lucilla i 12 

Antoninus Pius, nxtithfotne rare renterfes 

-is 
Antoninus Pius 6, Faustina io 

-16 

Marcus Aurelius 

-12 

Marcus Aurelius 4, Faustina jun. 10 

-14 

Lucius Verus 6, Lucilia 2, Commodus 8 

-16 
Commodus 4, Quinar. 1, Crispina 1. DittoQtncordia 1. Dis 

Genit a lib us 1 

-8 

Helvius Pertinax, r. Lalitia Temporum. cos. II. 
Clodius Albinus 2, Sept. Severus, Herculi defenfori 

Africa, and 6 others 
-12 
Septim. Sever us ; Adntentus Aug. Ditto, typus dinterf us in 

Carth. 6. Ditto Julia Pia 3 

-12 

Julia Pia, Diana Lucifer a biga, M ater Dteum Cereri fru-
gifera, Quinar. 4 ditto; Caracalla, Hercules and 

Bacchus, Lud. ftcul.fec. and 6 ditto 

&gt;-15 

51 

Caracalla 


i 

53 
54 

55 

( *5 

Diana in bigis 

) 

Lot (&quot;Cara CALL a; Diana in bigis ; Profefliofig. mi lit. cum duobus 
/ignis; Profeftio dua fig. ProfcBio Imp. Eques; Venus 

Victrix; mi Liberalitas Aug. Liber, vi ; Indulg. 

in Cartb. and 12 ditto 

2 Q 

.-* 

pPlautilla : Concordia felix, duafigura : Concordia 

/eterne, duafig. Propago Imperii, duafig. z ditto. 

Get A : Equus et Caftor; Vafia Pontificalia Severi dug. b 

fil. and 9 ditto 

Macrinus 

-6 / 

Macrinus I, Diadumenianus, Spes Publica, Typus fpei-z j 

Heliogabalus io; Julia Aquila Severa, fig.flan, ante. &apos; &apos; 

. 

aram fiacrificans Concord. 

_ 1 1 j 

Julia Paula ; Julia Maes a 5; Julia Soemi as i ; Alex, 

ander Severus 6 

A 
C Alexander Severus 6, and 1 anciently gilt; Julia Mam-

mea 5 

-S l2 J 

at&gt; i 

Julia Mammea ; Sallustia Barbia Orbiana; Maxu 

minus 7; Maximus, Principi Jwventutis 

-i&lt;^7 

/ 

&lt;* 

I 

-9-

-// -

-4. 

. 

/ 

&gt;. 

-d 

uO 

V 

t -s 

4-£&gt; 

0 

3 

*• &apos; 

&gt; 

57 

1 

58 { 

v Maximus: 

Pontificalia Pietas Augg. Gordianus AfrV 

ill or ia Aug. 

-

C Puppienus, Pax Publica ; Ditto ./war mutuus Augg. Bale J 

/ 

nus, Pietas mutua Augg. 
-J£ 

BaLBInus, r.Pietas mutua Augg. Ditto, r.ConcordiaAugg. Ditto 

Gordi kuvsCmshv.,PietasAugg. Gordianus Pius ,figura 

Equejiris : Liberalitas 11. &amp; 111. Venus Vifirix, and four 

ditto 
-

12&apos; 

Gordianus Pius 

-• 17 

Philippus, Sisculares Augg. Cerva ; Virtue Augg. Imperatore)bX 

Equites; JEternitas Augg. Elepbas ; Sasculares Augg. Leo 
Adventus Augg. lmperator. EqueJ. Fides Exeratus, triet&apos; 

figna milit. Felicitas Impp. in c rona laurea ; S^culares. 

^.v v 

Augg. Lupa. 9 ditto. Otacilla Severa, Seeculares, Augg. /\. ffti A 

Hippopotamus, and 5 ditto 
-23: 
@ 

Philippus Junior, Sasculares Cerva; Liberalitas in. Lib. miv 

&apos; 4 ditto. Trajanus Decius Panoniar; three different &apos; 

reverfies; Dacia ; Advent us ; Genio lllirici ; in all 11 f 

Herennia Etruscilla5 

-

/(Quintus Herennius7j Hostilianus 3; Trebonianu-

I 

Gallus io 

-20 

66 Volusianus 9; i^MILIANUS 3 

9 

67 ./Em il 1 an us 

-

-3 -*/ 

Valerian us, Virtue Augg. duo Imperatores ; Refiitutor orbis, * 

I 

6 

4 

ditto MariniaNa, Confiecratio 2 

-10 
GaLLIENUS,&apos;^o Imperatoresfacrificantes, Pietas Augg. Leg. 11. 
adiut. Aquila fuper Globum inter duo figna militaria ; Re 

fit tutors Galliarum ; Ara, &lt;vel bafis, cui Statua impcfita, 

Jovi Viflori; Imp. C&lt;ef. IA 5 ditto. Salonina, Aug. in 

pace Deae. Segetiee. 7 ditto 
-19 

*0 Liu. 

61 

62 

63 

64 

%\ 

f , v 

£ 

AX&apos; A 2 

-* 

A-1%&apos;-

/ .. // 

a 

0 

69 

0-/$* 


( 16 ) 

Lot 

/ u0 &apos;fO 

4 

5 
$ 

&lt;2,e&gt; 

4 

k 

3 &apos; 

°h 

f C&gt; &quot; o 

/•Lie. Valerianus Gallieni prater, deo Volcano, et 3 ditte&gt; 

1 

Lie. Corn. Valerianus Gallieni filius Pfuinar. 

Ditto Confecratio, Aqwla. 

Salon. Valerianus 4; 

/ 

Postumus 9 
-19 

f Dioclesianus i ; Maximianus i ; Maximinus 

1 ; Con-

1 

stantinus i ; Constantius i ; Valens 2; Gra-
tianus c witl&gt; a leaf of gold 1 ; Macs. Maximus i ; 

Hav. Victor, i; Honorius 2 ; Theodosius juniori; 

Jovinusi; Lib. Severus 1 ; Justinianus2 -17 

( A mofl beautiful Sett of the Twelve C^sars in Silver, with 

7 2 l 

feledt Reverfes &apos; 

73 Ditto GOLD MEDALS. 

7* i 

/ V /4\ 0 74 
/ * / * °7&gt; 

/ 

76 

0+7 

Tiberius 1, and Theodofius 1 

An ancient Britilh Piece, and 1 Gaulilh ditto 

An Half Sovereign of HenryVIII. and i ditto of Edw.VL-
Ditto of Edward VI. and of Elizabeth, milled 

2 

2 

2 

r 

2 

t /&apos; /A Bonnet piece of James VI. and a Sovereign of ditto &apos; -2 

/«&apos; 

79 Calicula, with the Head of Auguflus on the Revcrfe, rare 

* &quot; • « aa.. 

A 

PA-

Trajan, reverfe Forum Trajan, 

rare 

The TWELVE CAESARS. 

Si Julius Caesar. M. Mettivs 

82 Augustus C^tsar. A Bull. Augustus 

83 Tiberius. Jupiter fedene. pont. max. 
g, 5 Caligula. Caput Aug. radiatum. divus aug. pat. 

+ \ TRUE 

4 

85 Tie. Claudius. Caftrum Prastorium. imp. recept. 

86 

$ Nero, et Agrippina, Capita jugata. Quadrigsc Elephanfo-
O 

l rum. Ex. S. L. 

3 87 Galba. Corona quercea. s. p. l. r. o. b. c. s. 

A88 Otho. Figura fedens. pont. max. 

89 Vitellius. Fig. fedens cum patera et hafta. pont. max. 

0 

i Vespasianus. Figura alata. paci aucusti 

* if 0&gt; t Titus. Fortuna fuper aram. pontif. tr. pot. 

* fL* 

\ 

5 ^°mitianus. Imperator in quadrigis triumphalibus. cerma-

M*&apos; 0 J \ 

Nicus. COS. XVI 

. . 

% 

N. B. The Twelve Ctesars will be fold feparate or together, at the 

\ _ Option of the Company. 

13 /i 

5 /0 

/3 

F / N I S. 

f B n F 

V 

JUA 

i-PUPf/4 </unit>










































</text>
</tei>