<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">



<title>T.CEETtT 1999 






A 

CATALOGUE 

Of the Curious 

COLLECTION 

O F 

COINS and MEDALS, 

O F 

Charles Woolfe, Efq; 

Late of Haseley Court, in the 

^Cpunty of Oxford, 

AND OF 

GEORGE COOKE, Efq; 

Both iDeceas&apos;D; 

k 

Which (by Order of the Executors) 

Will be fold by A u c t i o n. 

By Mr. Langford and Son, 

At their Houle in the Great Piazza, Covent 

Gardifiy 

On Saturday the iSth of this Inftant February i ^69. 

--

« 

The laid Collection mav he viewed on Friday the 17th 

InOant, and till the Time of Sale, which will begin 

punctually at Twelve o&apos;Clock. 

Catalogues may be had gratis on the Days of Viewing, 

at Mr. Lang ford&apos;s aforefaic. </title>


<preface>Conditions of SALE. 

1[ft, 

B E higheft Bidder is to be the Buyers 

j[ and if any Dilute fhall arife between 

any two or more Bidders, the Lot fo difputed fhall 

be immediately put up again, and refold. 

2,dh\ No Perfon to advance lefs than 6d. under a 

Bounds above a Pound u; above Five Pounds 

2s 6d. and fo on in Proportion. 
%dly, The Purchasers are to give in their Names 

and Places of Abode, and to pay down Five Shillings 

in the Pound (if required) in Part of Payment of 

the Purchafe Money \ in Default of which, the 

Lot or Lots fo pur chafed, to be immediately put up 

again and refold. 

A*hly, The Lots fhall be fetched away with 

all Faults, at the Buyer&apos;s Expence, within One 

Day after the Sale 

, 

and the Remainder of the 

Purchafe Money absolutely paid on or before 

the Delivery. 

Lajlly, Upon Failure of complying with the above 
Conditions, the Money fo depofited in Part of Pay 

ment, fhall be forfeiteds the Lots uncleared within the 

One 
as aforefaid, fhall be refold, by publick 

or private Sale, and the Deficiency (if any) together 

with all Charges attending fuch Ref ale t 

fhall be made 
good by the Defaulters at this Sale* 

BrsF </preface>



<unit>t 4 ] 

Englifh Silver Medals. 

j j Jp * 

£. 

. A fine medal on the defeat of the Spanilh Armada 1588, 

2 • 

4 --Ditto of Archbilhop Laud, and 1 of Charles I. Virtute 

Ex Me 

/* 

/&apos; 

JL -

2. 

/* 
/ * 

/• 

/ 

/ -

, &gt;&apos; 

_ 

1 jr* 

Mp/bnA 

\(h^r K 

// • ^&gt; 28 ^1£t0 

&gt; 

families, Concordia Et Virtutem, and thfpanis T 7-)* 

profAgatii 

-

y J . 

jj # ^29 Ditto, Pugna Equejlris, Valio Gallorum Diruto, and 2 

v 

y^jr^A&lt; 

/ 

1 

on the peace 
3 

v 

v/ j 

30 Di to, George I. Advent. Aug. 1. Clementia Aug. iff 

£ 

Sociorum 

jj 

* 

,? 

• -3 1 Ditto, Duke cf Cumberland, George II, and 4 more, 

wt. 3 oz. (5 dwts. 

... 

• f -d~* 3 2 Oliver Cromwell, Charles I William and Mary, &amp;c. 10 

t f 

33 William HI. Anne, George I. and 2 of Jernegan&apos;s, rj 

\ 

j 

20 Ditto of Charles II. reverfe the royal arms, and one 

wuh Catherine 

-

(P ... 
21 Ditto, Magna Opera Domini, and 2 more 

-

/2 • b&apos; Ditto, reverie Catherine, finely preferred 

/ ----23 Ditto, reverie Fa vente Deo, cAtto 

JJ 

.24 Ditto of James II. reverfe Genus Antiquum 

-

1 

. 

b 2 y Ditto of William III. Rejiitutori, and 

1 of Mary, Velut 
inter Omnes 

--

Ditto of Anne, the inauguration, Blenheim, Gibraltar 

and Bonne 

//&gt;-27 Ditto, Infulu Cap ter, 2 on the union, and i on the peace 

2. -

/ • 

/ 

/ 

1 

j wt. 3 oz. 12 dwts. 

/ . //. G3 + James II. his Queen, the Chevalier, and 1 ditto, copper 

ûSl 

UQtTI Arne, ar fii&apos; &apos;-C fhd&apos;-rrr^n rrnfj wri 

/ &apos; / i r7 

1 

1 j &apos;dwts. 

. 1&amp; 

3^A meoal of the Royal Society, 1 of Jernegan&apos;s, a 

9 hr/pr&apos;, 

frlver farthing of George 1. and a copper medal of 

l \g) 

/ 

Mary 
--
4 

/2. • a 37 George fl ar.d Caroline&apos;s coronation medals 

/ *) .-^37 A fine medal of the learned Selden 

Roman Medals in Silver. 

I (tAeUfO XA 

it) 

. 

^38 

An Alexander, and 
5 Greek medals 

/ 

39 Lh.&apos;rty one conJuiar medals of as many different fami-

/ 6 --4°&apos; he twelve Caefars 

--

/ 

• 

/ O --J u &apos;ius, Aognltus, Claudius, Vitellius, Nerva, &amp;c. 

Ta T 

42 Got 

3* 

1 2 

30 

&apos; 

b/i .A/a... ( t-.~y vtTV A.&apos;/ /A. Alt&apos;, /J * 

. &apos;V 


[ 51 

ID 

,^42 Gordianus, 15 different reverfes, Philip 6, OUcilla 1. 

_ . 

£43 Mefcius Deems 2. Traj. Decius 3. Etrufcilla 2. Treb. 

/ 

Gallus 3. Volufianus 1. 

-
-

/£ . .44 Didia Clara, very rare, Albinus, rare 

-

_ 

45 Conftantine l, Max. Faulla, both rare 

46 Valerian 18. Marianianae 1. Gallienus 4. Salonina 3. 
Valerian jun. 4.. 

/y r ,47 Caligula, Domitilla, Pefcennius Niger, Did. Julianus, 

/ 

Gordian Africanus 1. and 4 more fpurious 

//--48 Eugenius, Valentinian, and 9 more found at Wantage 

in Berldhire 

--
049 A gold Byzantine, 1 filver ditto, and 1 more 

Gold Coins and Medals. 

7 _ 50 Eight foreign coins of France, Flanders, Germany and 

Venice, wt. 1 oz. I4dwt. 8 gr. 

1 b 

-

5 1 An Hanover ducat, 2 Venetian chequin?, and two 

more 
-

ei • 

52 A Dutch ducat, and 11 more pieces of foreign coin, 

/ 

wt. 2 oz. 6 dwt. 15 gr. 

£ 

# 

-53 A noble of Edward III. and 1 of Richard II. rare 

&quot; 54 An angel of Elizabeth, a fpur ryal of James I. and a 
fmall piece of Charles I. 

^55 An half fovereign of Henry VIII. broad piece of the 

Common wealth, a medal of UrbanVIll. aDaniih 

ducat, and 2 more, wt. 1 oz. 2 dwt. 2 gr. 

Charles II. coronation medal by Simon --

, 

-

Two pieces of Elizabeth, 5 of James I. and 8 of 
Charles I. wt. 4 oz. 3 dwt. 

Two rofe ryals, and 2 angels of Elizabeth, wt. 1 oz. 

5 dwt. 22 gr. 

A three pound piece of Charles I. and 9 more Eng-

lifh, wt. 2 oz. 13 dwt. 22 gr. 
A fine medal of Queen Anne and Prince George, wt. 

1 oz. 16 dwt. 2 gr. 

The coronation medal of his prefent Majefiy, wt. 

15 dwt. 16 gr. 

Oliver Cromwell&apos;s broad, well preserved 

a 

^Ênglifli Silver Coins. 

22 &apos; 

X J-f 

2 ~-c i * 

Z Avi tf-» 

a 

&quot;/ 

3 /jstst 

4&gt; 

&apos;V.. S 6 

6-7.^57 

s-s-w 

1 o -

-jsy 

3 

^^7 

r&gt; f /\) AK 

Jj-f 

J&apos; 

/ 

r 

5* 

60 

S--61 

^62 

j t V /&apos; . 

fr. &lt; 

1 

&lt;* ) 

a penny of Ethelred, and 10 more Englifh 

-. 

| j 

/. 2--64 Ditto of Henry I. r/?rr, and 3 of Henry If. 

-

2 

/y. _j65 Edward III groat, Phillip and Mary&apos;s Ihilling, two 

V7 

clipped half crowns, and 25 fmall 
66 Three 

J 

j if /&quot; V 

• 

bTufpi*,^£ &apos;»-1-^/my 

^-

* 

. 

^L\)&quot; 

V. ^&apos;y.. r J 

/£*&lt;. 
/eG) 

4t&lt;T\ 

29 


( 6 ) 

4 sO -66 Three me coins (truck in Aqaitaio 

&quot; 3 / /? 

7 &apos; -

67 Henry VII frilling, very rare 

-

S&apos; S -T A H VIII teftoon and 3 groats, Edward Vi bafe &lt;) L 

C\ 

//• b 68 H Zling, 

2 counterfeit dtao, and a piece of Mary 

1 

Queen of Scots 

O 

/i7--6o Edward VI 33 &lt;hilli»gs. and 6 fixpences, James I *i f 

&apos;j * (hillings, and 6 fixpences, wt. 11 oz. 

// 

70 Elizabeth&apos;s crown and half crown 

ft &apos;^3 8 (hillings, and 21 fixpences, wt. 8 oz. 

&apos; 7 

iadwt. 

&apos; 7* 

z 

&apos;L 

/*/£* 

-14 

half crown, 6 ditto of Charles I. and 1 of 

Newarke 

f . f J) . 73 Charles 1. a x (hilling piece, 2 crowns, and 7 half 

crowns 

• 

10&apos; 

/ &apos; /• 

-74 

-1 half crown, 16 (hillings, 3 fixpences, and 

9 

a groat 

* 

2*-

* 

/ * (P -75 

2 

-2 --7 6 

/ * 
/ 

2 

* 

/ 

/ 

1 

/ 

1 crown, 4 half crowns, and 17 more 
Briot&apos;s rare half crown, O Rex Da Facilem 

Cur/um 

y 77 Oliver Cromwell&apos;s crown, half crown and (hilling 

/ 78 Charles II 2 (hillings, 20 groats, 11 threepences, Z4 

twopences, and 3 1 pennies 

rf) ..79 Coins of feveral Engli(h princes, wt. 8 oz. 9 dwt. 

£ ,80 Ditto, wt. 3 oz. i 4 f dwt. 

^81 Milled pennies, twopences, threepences and groats, wt. 

7 oz. 3 dwt. 

J). ^8z Ditto, wt. 8 oz. 2 dwt. 

q . 

83 Oliver Cromwell&apos;s (hilling, a medal of Queen Anne, 

/ 

and 20 more, wt. 4 oz. tcdwt. 

2X &quot; 

22 
IT . 

flLtrit* 4 

Brafs and Copper. 

(p. (&gt; 

84. A Pertinax, and other coins, paduans, and fpurious 

j&quot; ^85 Greek, Roman, Foreign coins, &amp;c. 

-

ff, 86 A medal of Henry VIII. I of Lewis XIV. ar.d one 

more 

l&gt; 
. 

(j 87 Ditto of Queen Mary, and a parcel of Foreign and 

Englifh coins 

/ 

* 

£&gt;88 Ditto, a neat crofs, and 6 other coins 

/ / 89 Ditto of the Czar, 1 of Charles I. and 1 of Julius 

1 

III. 

18 /3ir* 

5 

? 

j 3* 

8 

XI 

^1 7 

L, 

32, 

.j (A go One hundred and fifty-two coins of Caraufius and Al* 

&apos; 

* 

leftus, with 5 copper plates, whereon are engraven 

feveral of thofe coins 

/) . Q • 9* An exceeding neat rofe wood cabinet, on a (land, with 4 fat f/^ry\ 

y p 

drawers, inlaid with ebony and ivory, and lined 

&apos; 

with green velvet 

w:b 

i -

. 

1 

V 

• 

Vo 

dfcrX? 


FINIS. 

I 1 


7. 

H 

« 





» 














» 







* 
















-</unit>




</text>
</tei>