<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
<title>% 



i -wmmmmmm-





CATALO G U E 

Of the curious and valuable 

LIBRARY 

O F 

Ebenezer MujJ&apos;el, Efq; 

Of Bethnal Green, 

Lately iDeceas&apos;tJ i 

Among which are many Original Manuscripts, and fe-
veral MifTals finely illuminated j aslikewife great Num 

bers of the liooks of the firfl: Printers, as Caxton, 
Pynson, Wynkyn de Worde, See. moft of which 

are perfect and in good Prefervation. 

Which (by Order of the Executors) 

Will be fold by Auction, 

By Mr. Langford and Son, 

At their Houle in the Great Piazza, Covent Garden, 

On Friday the 30th of May ij66, and the two 

following Days (Sunday excepted) 

Thefaid Books may be viewed on Thurfday the &apos;leth Injiant, 

and every Day after (Sunday excepted) till the Time 

of Sale, which will begin each Day punctually at Twelve 

o&apos;Ciock. 

Catalogues of which may be had gratis on the Days 
of Viewing at Mr. Langford&apos;s in the Great Piazza, 

Co vent Garden. </title>


<preface>Conditions of Sale. 

ift, F | A HAT the higheft Bidder is to be the 

Buyer ; and if any Difpute arife between 

two or more Bidders, the Book or Books to be put 
up again and re-fold. 

2d, That all the Books (not otherwife exprefTed) 

are fuppofed perfect ; but if any prove imperfect 

upon collating at the Place of Sale, the Buyers then to 
be at Liberty to take or Lave them. 
3d, That no Books (notwithjlanding they may 
prove imperfect) fliall be returned and accepted as 

fuch, after bought. 

4.th, That no Perfon advance lefs than 6d. un 

der a Pound, above a Pound is. and lb on in Pro 
portion. 

cth. That each Buyer pay Five Shillings in the 

Pound, in Part of Payment for each Lot, if de 

manded, and alfo give in his Name and Place of 

Abode. 

Lajlly, That the Books are .to be taken away at 
the Buyer&apos;s Expence, within two Days at fartheft, 

after the Sale is ended, and the Purchafe-Money paid 

on or before the Delivery ; in Failure of which, the 
Five Shillings in the Pound depofited in Part cf 

Payment, fhall be forfeited, the Books re-fold, 

and the Deficiency (if any) fhall be made good 

by the Defaulters at this prefenj Sale. </preface>


<unit>Jt 


mmm 



mm 



Bp. Bonner&apos;s Declaration of his Articles, and 3 more 

Decretum Aureum 1526, and 3 more 
Seven Catholick Tradls 1547 to &gt;550, and 2 more 
29 Byrd&apos;s Paule and Demas 
30 Bayle&apos;s Englifh Votaries 
3&apos;i New Teftament 

-

32 De Imitat. Chrilti 

15 Ro 

1560 
1542 
*543 

33 Bp. Gardner&apos;s Refutation of George Joye 1546, very 

fcarct 
34 Bp. Gardner&apos;s De Vera Obedientia, and 2 fcarce Trafts, and 

2 more 

35 Doftor and Student, firf: td&apos;ition 15 31 --George Joye&apos;s 

Conjectures 1^48 

36 Hift. of Marc. Aurelius *559* and 2 more 
37 Bayle&apos;s Ymage of both Churches 1503, and 2 more 

38 Cicero&apos;s Bckee of Duties 1556 
John&apos;s Knox&apos;s Admo 
nition 1534, and 2 more, very rare 

39 King Henry Vlllth&apos;s Primer 

1 3 38, very rare 
40 Rofar. Joh. tc Mariae 14^9, and 2 more 
41 Miffale 14&lt;53, and 4 more 

42 The Boke called the Governor, for a further Account of this 
rare Lot fee the Beginning 
43 Vita Chrifti 1336-~-Bib. Sac. ac Nov.Teftam. 1526, 

and 2 more 

44 Cowper&apos;s Chronicle 1565 -Mirour of Magiftrate* 

1587 

45 Bullinger&apos;s 50 Godlie Sermons 1577-Holfome Advice in 

30 Sermons, by the L. Bp. of Lincoln *558 
46 Pylgrimage of Perfection 

printed by Pyvfon 1528 

47 The 13 Bukes of Eneados, tranflated into Scottifh Metre bi 

Gawen Docglafs, very rare andJint 
*553 

48 The Boke of Knowledge, and : more 
49 Latymer&apos;s fiuitfuU Sermons 1557 
Raftell&apos;s Mirour of 
the World 1536 

;o Ligthgowe&apos;s Travels, and 2 more Trafts, and 3 more 

51 Queen Mary&apos;s Prymcr 
*55? 

Anniball and Scipio, by Cope 1568-Wiggiffe&apos;s Anfwer 
to a Libell 1472 -Grain. Defpauterii 1535 
Peirce Plowman&apos;s Vifion 1550-Coverdale&apos;a New Tefta-

ment 
Funcke&apos;s Chronicle 

Henry VlUth&apos;s Prymcr 

* 

1 

-

*536 

Liber Feltivalis 

-

*483 

Conqueft of the Weft Indies, very fcarce 

1555 

Luther&apos;s Comment. 1575. and 3 more 
Taverner&apos;s Epiftles and Gofpels -hooper&apos;s Anfwer to the 
Bp of Winchelter 

Zurych 1547 

59 J u gge &apos; s NewTeflament 1532 

King Henry Vlllth&apos;s 

neceffary DoCtrine, or Prayers for the Church 

&apos;Win. 

Baldwins Balades of Solomon 1549 

MAMU-




( 5 ) &apos; 
MANUSCRIPTS. 

60 

TEtutif. curiofa Tab. Altronorn. or mofil ancient and curious 

\ Agronomical Tables, finely i/Iam. and g more 

lY&quot;&apos; 61 Sermo de Wimbledon, or Richard of Wimbledon&apos;s Sermon 

preached at Pau1e3 Crofs 1388, in the Reign of Ric. II. 

&apos;very fine prejcrration (Eng.) 
62 Opere Johan. Wickliffe, or the Works of John Wickliffe, 

in &apos;very fine prefiervalion ( Eng.) 

63 TVo Manuale, or two Manuales of Devotions, ilium. 
64 /Epiiiol. &amp; Le&amp;iones in ufu Sarum, or a raoft ancient Col 

lection of the Epiilles and .Leflons ufed by the Church 

of Salifhury (Eng.) 
***&apos; 6g Two Breviaries, &lt;very curious 
66 Sermcnes, cr very ancient Sermons and other Divine Trails 

(La,.) 

67 Sir John Maundeville&apos;s Travels, very valuable 
Me*-68 Miffale, or a Miffialfinely ilium. 
69 Gofpela St. Marcos, or the Gofpel according to St. Mark, 

Eng. 

70 Gofpela &amp; Epift. St. Johan. &amp; St. Jacob, or the Gofpel and 
Epiftles of St. John and St, James, Eng. 
71 St. Clement, de Cantaur. Hill, de Quatuor. Evar.gelis, or 
St Clement, of Canterbury his Storie of the Foure Bocs 

of the Gofpelerie?, &apos;very curious 

Two Miffals, finely ilium. 
73 Pfa! terium David, and 

1 more 

Vetud IT. Nov. Teftasn. in Erfe, or a mod ancient Trarfla* 
tion of. the New Tedament into Welch, very curious 

75 A Breviary, finely wrote and prefier-ved 

76 Speculum Ecclefne, or the Mirroure of the Church, by Sf. 

Edmund, finely preferred 

77 Bib. Sac. &amp; Nov. Tell, or a mod ancient and curious Bible 

and Tedament, tnofi exquifistely nxrote, and finely pre 
ferred 

t 

7S Quedam Deccrpta ex Solom, or Extradls from the Proverbs 

&apos; of Solomon, and 1 more 

79 VetudifT. Tranflat. in Ang. de Boetius de Confolat. or a 
mod ancient Translation into Englilh Verfe of Boetius 

de Confolatione, fine prefierration 

Vita Chrihi, or moll ancient Tranflation into Englilh of the 
Life of Chrill, finely preferred 
Vetuftiff. Tranflatio de Tedam. Jefu Chridi, or a mod cu 
rious and valuable ancient Tratfflation of the New Te-&gt; 
/lament, for a further Account of this rare and valuably 
Lot fee the Beginning 
82 Magna 


82 Magna Charta, de Ferefta Statuta de Marllridge, ice. very 

ancient and rare, Lat. 

83 Ovidii Epiftola, in l.at vertfinely prr/erved 
84 Vita St. Katherine, or the Lite of St. Catherine, in Eng. 

finely pre/erved 

8; Vetuftifl. Chronicon,an ancient Chronicle, in Eng. 

86 Legenda Acrea, or the Golden Legend, very ancient and 
finely prrfierved 

87 Orationes Romanum, or felett Prayers of great Antiquity 

ufed by the Roman Church, Lat. 

Legenda San&amp;orum, or the Legend of Saints and Martyrs, 

&amp;C .finely vurote, andin great prrficrvation 
89 Mifiale, or a Mifialefinely prejerved 

Egidius de Regim. Priucip. or Egidius on the Policy of 

Princes, written Anno 
1 280, and dedicated to Philip the 

Fair K. of France, finely ilium, a moft rare MSS. ii in fine 

prefervation 

Tradatus de Venatione &amp; Nat. Animal, or the Maiftre of 

Game and the Nature of Ar.iniaies, wrote An. 1400, 

finely preferredand ilium. 

Chronicon Robertus de Gloucefter, or Robert of Glouce. 

fter&apos;s Chronicle, wrote in Henry 11 Id&apos;s Time, finely pre 
jerved 

Brute five Chronicon Anglia, or Brute a moft ancient Eng-
glifh Chronicle 

Nich. Uptoni de Studio Militari Lib. Quat. or Nich. Upton 
on the Art of War, and the Origin of Heralds and Bla 
zoning of Arms, curioujly col. andfinely preferred, Eng. 

Poema di Bocc.de Gubermat. Princip. &amp;c. or Boccius on 

the Government of Princices tranflated into Englifh, 
and wrote An. 1410, fine pre/ervation 
96 Legenda, or a moft ancient Legend in Englifh, ivitbmany 

illuminations 

Liber Diflus Miroure, or the Boke called the Miroure, very 

rare and ancient 

Chronicon Anglia, or a Chronicle of England, by Mathew 
of Weltminfler, finely pre/erved and ilium. Eng. 

Vetulliff. Traftatus de Medicinas, or a moft ancient Treatife 
of Medicine and Phyfick, voiib many marginal Notes, fine 

prejervation 

Second 




Seond Day&apos;s Sale, Saturday, May 31. 

t 

Twelves, Octavo, Quarto, and Folio. 

Lot 

100 \ Large Parcel of various 

, q 1 

Baxter, aud 10 more 

102 Hill&apos;s Lexicon, and 12 more 

,03 Macarius&apos;s Homelies.and 5 more Sermons, Sec. 
104 Religious Trafts, 6 vol. various 

105 Fcbrifugum Magnum, and 4 more 
106 Monumenta Kempiana, and 6 more 

107 Important Inquiry, and 5 more 

108 Religious Courtfbip, and 4 more 
109 Williams&apos;s Sermons, 3 vol. aod 3 more 

no Colleflionof Sermons, and 3 more, 4to. 

111 Hiftoricall Proofs of the Loyalty of the Prefbyterians 

from Queen Elizabeth to Charles IT. and 4 more 

112 Afls of Parliament from 7th King William to 3d of Anne, 

6 vo 1 . 

113 Ditto from the 4th of Queen Anne to iftcf George I. 

7 vol. 

114 Ditto from the 

1 ft of George I. to 6th ditto, 6 vo). 

115 Ditto from the 7th to the 12th of ditto 

116 Ditto from the 1 3th of George I. to 5th of Geo. II. 

117 Ditto from the 6th ditto to 9th ditto of Keeble&apos;i Sta 

tutes, 2 vol. 

124 EL 


( 8 ) 

Elliot&apos;s Image of Government, and Peirce Plowman&apos;s 
Vifions 

Ji 12 q Henry VIHth&apos;s Primer, and i more 

Vita Chriiti 

Wynken de Worde l 5 2 9 
V. Ortus Vocabulorum 

. 

^.1506 

^128 The SalilburyePrymer 1557. and 2 more 

129 Holfome and Catholyke Do&amp;rine. by the Bp. of Lincoln, 
and the Buke of 83 Queltions, by Winget 

1561 

A Declaration of the Ten Commandments, &amp;c by Joanne 
Hopper 1548 

The Governour, by Elliot *1553* 

and 

1 

more 
131 Regimen Sanitatis Salerni 1501 

The Order of the 

Hofpitales of Henry VIII. and Edward VI. and 1 

more 

132 The Confeflyon of the Fayth of the Germans in 153, 

tranflated by Taverner 1536, and 

1 

more 

133 The Deyoute Treatife, called the Pilgrimage of Perfec 

tion 

by Wynkyn de Worde 

1 9 31 

y&apos;* I34 Legenda Angliae, or Legend of England printed ly P jnjon 

fp, 4 &apos; i ; 

1516 

135 A profitable and necefTarye Doftrine by the Bp. of Lon 

don 
-

1521 

136 The Voiage and Travailleof Sir John Maundeville 
137 Horse Virginis Marie, moft curioujly printed $n •vellum, with 

emblematical borders, and fine illuminations 
Paris 150* 
138 6aynt Auguftyns Rule 1525, .arid 3 more 

139 The Expoficyon of the 5iltand 3Cth Pfalmcs, and the 

Pyftels and Gofpels 1538, and 3 more 

140 The Tragoedie of Barnardine Ochine 1549, and 3 

more 

141 Gower de Con&apos;cfiione Amantis, in Englifii Verfe 

15^4 

142 MifTale ad ufum Sarifbarienfe, printed on milium, with 

cuts 

-

1526 
143 Legenda Aurea 
Bouiilion 1514 

144 Conftitutiones Legitime 1504-Boochas&apos;s Fall of Princes, 
in Englifh Verfe, by Lydgate 

.y&apos; 145 Caxton&apos;b Chronycle, very fair 

1480 

y 146 Scala Perfcdfionis, by Caxlon, -very fair -*494 

147 Cranmer&apos;s Anfwer to Gardiner 

1551 

. 

jr 148 Vetuflifl. Bib. Sac. ac Nov. Teftam. or a moft ancient 

Bible and New Teftam. Latin 

1494 

149 Caxton&apos;s Holy Land Wars 

1481 

j&quot; 150 C«7.v/ff«YSiegeof Troye 

1482 

151 The Floure of the Ten Commandcments by Wjnkin de 

ae Worde 1521 

r 1 52 Liber Sanitatis, or a Treatife on Herbs, &amp;c. a mojl rare 

and&apos;valuable Bake, finely preferred, cuts coloured 

1491 




1 53 

&gt;54 

&gt;55 

i s6 

[9] 

Legenda Aurea, imper, by Caxton -Miflale ad ver. Sarif-

bur, with cuts 1555 
The Grete Herbal, theVertuofe Book by Pet.Travers, of Di* 
ftyllacion ofWaters and Herbes -The noble Expery-
ence of the handyWorke of Surgeons, ail byTreverst 585 

Ranulph Mcnke of Chefter his Polychronicon Wynkyn de 

JVorde 1495 

Bartholomeco de Proprietatibus, tranflated into Eng. fine 

prefervation 

-

* 5 3 5 

157 The Holy Bible and Teftament, printed at the Command 

of K Henry VIII. very fair andfine 

158 Grafton&apos;s Chronicle, and an old Bible 

159 Chron. Nuremburgenfis, by H. Schedell, with many tuts, 

five prefervation 

-----

1 493 

-

160 Vitas Patrum, or Lives of the Fadirs in Eng. by Caxton\48 5 

Fafciculus Tcmporum, or a very anciem Chroni 

cle 1476 

, &apos; 

*61 Tully de Sene&amp;ute, in Eng. by Caxton-Bulleine&apos;s Bul-
warke of Defence againil all Sickneffe, with many cuts 

162 Hollingfhed&apos;s Chronicle, 2 vol. 

163 Barclay&apos;s Ship of Fools, with cuts 
164 Guido Bonatus de AHronomie, with cuts 1491, and 1 

more 

&apos;&apos;if-165 Dial! of Princes -Caxton&apos;s Chronicle, imperfect 

y 166 Pylgrimage of Perfection by Pynfon, and r more 

167 Caxton&apos;s Chronicon-Ditto, by Julian Notary, and Cax-
ton&apos;s Pylgrimage of Perfection 

* 168 Polychronicon 
printed by Trevors 1567 

\ / sf 169 ^Efop&apos;s Fables 

by Pynfon 

MA NUSCR1P1 S. 

/ 

ITO PSal terium David, and very old Tranflation of the New 

Ted. 
171 Two Meures, Catholique, ilium. 
172 A molt curious Pi,deer Boke of the Lord Beaumont, fee a 
farther Account in the Book, fine 
&gt;73 VarisPreces &amp; Ledtiones, or various Prayers and Leffons, 

fire 
174 Memoriale Sanftorum. or Memorial of Saints 

s}, -x ~l 7 &gt; Miflale, mofi txquitely illuminated, andfinely preferred 

176 Bib Sac, ac Nov. Teil. with the Concordance in Lat. 

very ancient, but mofi curioufiy wrote and ilium, andfinely 
preferred 

177 Hora-Chtifti, ilium, and Pfa&apos;mes Dav : d, ditto 

t 

V dr &gt;7 S Breviary in Eng, very ancient ana finely ilium. VVWI/&apos; 

^179 Ditto, ditto, auto 

B 

180 r ^ 


180 Legerda Antiqua, fine prefer vat ijn 
j 81 A Collodion of very ancient Sermons 

182 Heores, or Hours, a Cath.cluk Rrck of Prayer, rr.ojl n.tgni-

&gt; 

ficently ilium. and bound in moro(ct) 

183 Nov Teftam. or the New Teftament in Lat. very finely 

•urofe and pre/erved 

184 Tradatus tie Relig. or a Treatife on Religion, &amp;c. very 

ancient ana finely preserved 

18c An ancient Chior icle, Lat. 

186 Horse Chiifti, or Prayers in Commemoration ofJefus thrift, 

mofil exquifitely ilium. voith many finefigures 

p 187 Liber de Saoientia, or the £ook of Wifdom, wry ancient, 

/ &quot; fivppofied the 0&gt; iginaJ 

188 Expc htio de quibuldam Scriptura part&apos;bu&apos; Sacra, or an Ex-

pofition of feveral Parts of Holy Writ very amienf 

189 Srmulus Corfcient&apos;a, or a Spur to the Confcuo.ce. by Nich. 
de Weftem, in Eng. Verle, very ola.juppojcdan Original 
Legenda de Thom? de Arundel, or Tho. of Arundel&apos;s Le 

gend, in Erg. \ctic,fine prefervaticn 

191 Vetuftiftm. Hift. Nat. or a moll ancient Natural Hiflory, 

4 

finely prefi rved 
Pfal David, cr the Pfalms of David, ilium, and vl ell pre 
ferred 
Poema Licati, or Lydgate*.-Poem on the Story of CEilipur, 

&amp;c. in Englilh Vcrfe, very curious, and vcell preferred 

194 Tradatus de Sac. Scripturae, or a Treatife on Holy Writ 

J&quot;ex fk 

and New Tellament, with a Compendium of the Bible, 

in Verfe, Eng. 
195 Compendium Morale de quibufdam Did Sc fac. Antiq.qr 
a Compendium of the Sayings and Deeds of the An-

! J 

cients, written by Roger de Walton, Canon qf London, 

•very fine preservation 

196 Odo Libri Bb Sax. or the eight firft Books of the Old 

US SS 

Teftament, finely ilium. 

197 Poema de ExitioTroja, or a liately Poem of the Defl uc-
tion of Troy, written by J of of Exeter, fine prejerva-

iion 

-

1 * t4 

198 Juftiniani Irftit. orjuftinian&apos;s InPutu&apos;es, *1vith many margi. 

val Notes, fine preservation 

199 Hift. Anglia Venerab. Bede, or Venerable Bede&apos;s Hill, of 

England, Lat.finely prejerved 




( I&apos; 

Third Day&apos;s Sale, Monday, June 2. 

twelves, Otlavo, Quarto, and Folio. 
Lot 

200&quot; 

201 

A Large Parcel of various 

Goldman&apos;s Latin and Englifh Dictionary, and 3 

more 
20 
203 

Platma Vita Pontificum, and 5 more 

Bertii Comment, Rerum German, and 3 more 

204 Hudibr .L Redivivus, and 4 more 
205 Thefauius Geograph cu , a Collection of King&apos;s Speeches 

1 

and other rraCts. and 

1 

more 

206 Watfon&apos;sSermons-Stillingfleet&apos;s Sermons, and Burgefs on 

St. john 
207 Bacon&apos;s Natural Hill.-Or&apos;ando Furiofo, in Englifh, with 
many cuts, and Rufhworth&apos;s Hid. Collections, 3 vol. 

208 Seguina Numifmata Antiqua 
Spanhemu Numifmata, 

2 vol 

209 Cuperi Harpocrates, with plates 

Aoguftorum Ima 

gines, with plates 

Strada Numifmata Nummi Bri-

tannici 

210 Three Prefentation Books to James I. and Charles 1. and 

Charles II. curioujly hound 

211 Scott&apos;s Difcoverie of Witchcraft -Wickliffe againft beg 

ging Friars, ana 3 more 

. 

212 Biolia Pifturis Illuflrata, or the Bible illuftrated, with 

o 

many plates 

The firft Gate to the Hebrew Tongue, 

by Robertfon. and 1 more 
213 Douay Bible and New Teftament, 3 vol. very rare 

214 Catalogues of Dr. Mead, &amp;c. marked, and 6 more 

215 Rights of the Chriftian Church, and 9 more 

Old printed Books. FOLIO. 

216 y^Icero de Officiis 1508 

Plynii zdi Hiftoriae Na-
turalis 15 14-Catullus. Tibullus &amp; Propertius, 

cum Comment. 1491 
Salluft, cum Comment. 

1 5 2 3 

217 LaCtantius, with MSS. Notes 1478 -Diog. Laer 

tius 1475 

Salluft 1514 -Ovid. Metamorph. 

* 5*9 

£2 

218 Vir-


mmm 

&apos;-Z-L, 

0l+ / 

/o-6 

( 12 ) 

218 Virgilius, cum Comment. &amp; Figuris 1522-Ovid. Me-

tam. 1483 

Livy 1511-Boetius 1508 
219 Terentius, with many MS. Notes and Platts 1493-Quin* 
tillian 14-3 

220 Bib. Sac. cum Comment, very ancient, without a date, and 

1 more 

./-221 The Workes of Sir Tho. More, Knygbt, 2 vol. 

&gt;537 

222 Drayton&apos;s Polyolbion-Sleidan&apos;s Commentaries 
223 Stowe&apos;s Annals-Bp. Jewel&apos;s Wqrks, and 

1 

more 
224 Suetonius 1496 
C&apos;odicis Theodofiani 1528 
225 Platina de Vita Pontificum 14-79V and 1 rpore 
226 Firmamentum Trium Ordinum Sti Frahcifci 1512 --
Sermonrs Hieronimii 1512, and 3 more 
227 A Godlie Sermon preached at&apos;Paules Crofle on Quinquag. 

Sunday, by R. Wymbleton 13.88 -A Refutation of 
Bp. Wincheller&apos;s deike Declaration, by Geo joye 1546, 

« 

;ni 2 more 

228 Peirce Plowman&apos;s Vifron 

The Birth of Mankynde, 
otherwife named the Woman&apos;s Bookp IC4.0 
The 

Seynge of Uryns and off all the Colours of it 1525-

Certayne Godly Difcourfes of Bp. Latimer, and Bp. 
Ridley, during tneir Imprifonment 1574, and 1 

more 

229 Horae Marias?, with many figures, and fine emblematical bor 

ders 

1508 -Archbp. Crahmer&apos;s Defence of the Eng. 

Sacraments 

Hynorum&apos;ad u,f. Sarifburienfe, by Ju 

lian Notary 1503 

230 Hall&apos;s Chronicle-Heath&apos;sChronicle 

; 

23: Legenda Aurea, or the Goldpn Legend printed by Julian 

&amp; Notary 

1 5o3 

Tydall&apos;s Bible and New Tefta-

ment 

232 Wigon&apos;s Chirurgerye 1541 -pChaucer&apos;s Works 1561 

&quot; 233 The Holy Bible and New Teftamelu, with Cranmer&apos;s Pre-

d 

face, fine frrftrvation 

• 

234 The Holy Bib e and New Teftam.ent 

by Grafton 1 540 

235 Grafton&apos;s Chronicle 

Hollinglhed&apos;s Chronicle, Vol. 

1 and 2. 

236 The Doftrine of Sapyrr.ce 

by Caxton 1476 

237 The whole Workes of Tyndall, Fryth, and Dr. Barnes, 

very yearce 
*573 

238 The Shype of Fools, Lat. St Eng. with cuts printed by 

yv 

Pynfcn 

1542 

•549 
Monke of 

239 Fabian&apos;s Chronicle 

-

240 Tyndall&apos;s Bible 

-

241 The Tragedies of John Bocchas, by Lidgate 

Bury, fine pre/er-vation 
242 Breviarium Romanum 1480-Bib: Sac. &amp; Nov. Teflaro. 

Venet. 1475 

243 Chau* 


. «tw«&apos; 

&apos; i:b! 


» 

* 


258 

A Jewifh MSS.-Observations on Addifon&apos;s Travels, 

with many plates, and i more 
Ancient Hymns, with the Pfalms of David, ilium. --

Breviarium in ufu Frat. Benedict, or the Breviaries ufed 
by the Benedi&amp;ine Friars 

Horae Mariae, or the Hours of Prayer to the Virgin Mary, 

fnely illuminated and preferred, this Book was writtenfor 

and ufed by Queen Mary 

261 Vetuiiiff. de Tranflat Nov. Tell, or a moft ancient Tranf* 

lation of the New Teiiament into Eng. fine prejervation 
Avery fine Manufcript unknown 
A Catholick Prayer Book, illuminated, and a Colleflion of 

old Sermons 

&apos; 

264 A very fine MifTall, mofi exquifitelyilluminated, with many 

/ 

figures, and a very fine border 
San&amp;a Bernardi Diflertatione &amp;.de Veritate Theologies, or 
St, Barnard on Difpenfations, and other Theological 
Truths 
266 The 


r&apos;y f 

f H ) 

266The Epiflles, Gofpells and Leflbns for the Church through 

out the Year, very ancient andfine 

yf 267 Stimulus Confcientiae, in Eng. Verfe, for a further Account 

of tbit valuable Hook fee tie Hefreeing 

Venerab. Bed* Hilt. Ang. or Venerable Bede&apos;s Hill. of 
Enj,/f«r prefervat on 
*69 Ordinal of St. Bridget, moft magnificently illuminated, andfine 

prejer-vaticn 

270 Venerab. Bed* Expofitio Epillolar. Canonices, or Bede&apos;s 

J 

Expofition of the feven Canonical Epiilles, fne prefer-
vat ion 
271 Vetufliff. M. S. S. de Legibu? &amp; Originalibus Scriptis, or 

an Account of Original Writs, with 
, many marginal 
Notes, finelypreftrvtd 

272 Miffale in u&lt;u Saxonicorum Anglorarn, or the Book of 
Prayers as uf«d by the Saxons in England at their firll 

Converfion, Lat. &amp; Eng. fine prefervation, vei-y cu 

rious 

273 Expofitio de Sac. Scriptura, or Commentary on fevcral Parts 

of Holy Writ, very old 

&lt;/&gt;is 274 Miffaie, cr the Miffale wrote 1404, mod magnificently and 

ff 

beautifully ilium, with a great many figures 

27c Bib. Sac. &amp; Novum Teftament very fine and very an-

MT -• rent 

276 Traftatus de Divinitateir Arte Moriendi, or a Treatifeon 
Divinity, &amp;c. this curious Book was written for and 
given tothe Abbey of Deptford for the Ufe of Dame Per-
r.ella Wrottefly. a Sifter of the faid Abbey, by William 
Baron, Efc; ilium, finely preferved 
277 Ranulphus Ciftrenfis Hid. Univerfaiis, or Ranulph a Ce-

--

fteriian Monk&apos;s Univerfal Hiftory, illuminated, very 

ancient and fine 

. 

^^278 Poema Edmundi Rex Anglcae, or Lydgate&apos;s Hill, of St. Ed-
mund the King, in Eng. Verfe,finefy ilium, fivitb a great 

many figures 

279 L.egenda Aurea, or the Golden Legend, finely wrote and 

\y 

illuminated 

280 Plalterium Romanum, or the Catholick Pfalter, finely 

wrote, and nobly illuminated 
2S1 Bartholcmei de Proprietatibus, or Father Bartholomew on 

the Properties of Natural Boddies, very ancient, and a 

very fine Book 

282 Articulis Originates Pads Unionis &amp; Confederations inter 
Olivarium Protedl.&amp;c ic Polentes Domines Belgic®, or 
\ 

the Original Articles of Peace between Oliver Cromwell 

and the Sta f es General 1654, a moft valuable MSS.fign-

^edby 5 Englifii Comrmffioners, 4 Dutch, and byOliver 

&gt;v 

283 Le* 




( *5&quot;&gt; 

283 Legenda Sanflorum, or the Legendary Lives of upwards r 

of ?oo Saints and Martyrs, in &apos;very fine PiefcrvAtion, ** 

finely wrote 

284 Vetuftifl&quot;. Bib. Sacra; Si Nov. Teflam. or moll curious, 
ancient, and very fine Bible and New Teflatnent, in 
Lat. 

285 Iiocchas de Cafu Principutn, or Bocchas on the Fall of &amp; 

Princes, in Eng. Verfe, finely wrote, ilium nnd preferred 

FINIS, 

r 











1HI </unit>

































</text>
</tei>