<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
<title>CATALOGUE 

OF THE VALUABUS 

MUSEUM 

O F 

THE LATE 

MATTHEW DUANE, F.R.&amp;A.S. 

PART IL 

CONSISTING OF 

His fuperb Collection of antient and modem 

G E M S, 

Statues, Bufts, Lares, Infcriptions, Vafes, 

Lamps, Fibulas, and other Re 

mains of Antiquity ; 
Together with his Collection of B O O K S 

relating to Coins and Antiquities : 

As alfo various Copper Plates of Coins and Medals, by Barto-
lozzi and Others, particularly the Heads of Jupiter Dodo-
naeus and Tryphon ; with his complété Sériés ofSyrian Kings, 

in Twenty-eight Plates, ail by Bartolozzi. 

WHICH WILL BE 

SOLD by AUCTION, 
By Mr. GERARD, 

At his H O U S E, in 

LITCHFIELD-STREET, 

St. ANNE&apos;s, S O H O, 

On Mo n DA y, the 13th of June, 1/85, and 

the Four following Days, 
To be viewed on Frlday, the nth, Saturday, the i 2th, and 
each Day till the Time of Sa/e, which will begin ac 

HALF after ELEVEN o&apos;Clock precifely. 

CATALOGUES to be had at Mr. Gerard&apos;s aforefaid. </title>


<preface>Conditions of Sale. 

I. ( 

J m&gt; HE bigbeft bidder to betbe buyer ; and, if any 

difpute Jhall arife between any two or more bid 

der s, tbelotfo difputed to be put up again. 

II. No perfon to advance lefs tban fixpence ; above 

cnepound, one Jhilling ; above five pounds, two fhiU 

iings andfixpence \ andfo in proportion. 

III. Ÿhe pur chafers are to give in their names and 

places of abode, if required, and to pay down fivefhil-

lings in the pound in part of tbe purchafe-money 

-, in de-

fault ofwhich, the lot or lots fo purcbafed to be immé 

diately put up again and re-fold. 

IV. &apos;The lots to befctched away, witb ail faults, at 

the buyer*s expence, within one day after the fale. 

Lajily. Upon failure of cotnplying witb the above 
conditions, the money, fo depofued in part of payment, 

(hall be fcrfeited 

-, 

the lots, uncleared within the time a-
fcrefatâ, fisail be refold by public or private fale 

-, 

and 

the deficiency, (if any,) together with the charges atten-

ding fuch re-fale, Jhall be made gosd by the defaulters at 
&apos;ibis fale. </preface>


<unit>A CATALOGUE, 6m 

Second Part, 

FIRST DAY&apos;s SALE. 

Mondaj, J une 13, 1765. 


20 Elcven métal rings, two fet. Tbefe ufied to be nvorn by tle 

Roman fiaves oj tbe lovuer clafs. 
21 Six antique heads and a lamp in terra cotta, two Indian de-
ities in bronze, a bronze head, a fteelyard, and other 
antiquities. 

22 A bull of Serapis, a figure of Ifis and Orus, i, ditto 
of Ifis z, Canopus i. 

23 Abuftof Serapis, a figure of Ifis and Orus, five figures of 

Ifis, and a buft. 
24 A fine figure of Jupiter, a buft of Juno, Venus juft corne 
from bathing, and a figure of Minerva. 
25 A very élégant figure of Apollo and one of Juno, 

26 Perfeus with the head of Medufa. 

27 Juno, and a Venus juft corne from the bath. 
28 A fine figure of Ifis and Orus. 
29 A fine figure of Angerona, very remarkable, not only on 
account of the lcarcity of figures of this goddefs, but 

alfo for the fingularity of the veftments. It is the very 

figure dèfcribed by Count Caylus in bis Recueil d&apos;Antiquités. 

20 Three antique bronze figures, a bronze head, and two 

lamps. 

-• s» 

ji^Three antiem oriental bowls, with inferiptions. 

Far tous Curiofities. 

;.~32 A very curious magnet, compofed of fixteen bars. 

33 The great féal of Henry VII. appending to a curious illu-

minated deed, and a grant of Robert de Thornham to 
the monaftery of Reinalle, in the çth of King John, 

with a very fine and perfedt leal appending, on the re-

verfeof which is a beautiful antique head of Plato. 
34 The great féal of Elizabeth, two antient deeds, and a cu 

rious paper relating to the pretender. 

35 A book containing various fpecimens of writings, of diffe 
rent kinds of paper, &amp;c. and a great number of engra-
vingsof coins and other antiquities. 
36 Various engravings of coins, gems, and other antiquities. 
37 A very curious MS. of the book of Efther, in Hebrew, or-
namented with a great variety of curious drawings. 
38 Ditto, in a fmaller letter. 
39 A variety of MSS. in the Arabie, Turkilh, Perfian, Tan-

gutic, Chinefe, and other oriental languages. 
40 Two very curious Greek MSS. and a printed Greek indul 

gence. 


Seven ditto and a ring. 
Three large entaglios and a cameo ring. 
A curious antient gold ring with an infcription, a filver 
ditto, and a fibula. 
45 A large and curious gold ring, fet with a very fine fapphire, 
Jaid to be found in dtgging a grave in Winchefer cathédral. 

The head of Velta, in cameo, jacinth, fet round with 

garnets. 

A very élégant fcarabaeus, fardonyx, fet in a ring ; a cameo 
in the original Roman fetting, and a gold ring of the 

lower empire fet with a, fapphire. 
An AEgyptian abraxas, with Greek charadlers, in the ori 
ginal gold fetting. 

49 The head of Msecenas, a cameo, onyx, and a Grecian 
philofopher, in entaglio, amethyit, with a pâlie from 

it. 
49*Head of Severus, in entaglio, onyx, and Perfeus with the 
head of Medufa, in entaglio, cornelian, and one more* 
50 A head of a Roman matron, on entaglio, very fine, corne-
liao.. 

51 A boy&apos;s head in cameo, élégant, amethyft. 
5 i*Auguftus and Livia, in entaglio, green jafper, and 2 more. 

52 The head of Ahenobarbus and his wife, in entaglio, root 
of emerald, in a ring, very curious, and undoubtedly an 

tique. 

53 A Pegafus, in entaglio cornelian, and a Cupid, ditto, Sy-
iian garnet. 

54 A nymph fleeping, and a meflenger of vidlory, both enta 

glios in cornelian. 

55 The head of a bacchante and two mafks, onyx, both in ca 

meo. 

5p6 A fow in entaglio, nicolo, aGanymede in entaglio,cornelian, 
fine work, and undoubtedly antique. 

57 A joung head, in entaglio, cornelian, infcribed -» 

tvrv^a.»oç. 

58 A hunter killing a lion, in entaglio, cornelian, good work. 
59 Ptolemy Neoteros, in entaglio, cornelian, fnework. 
bo A bearded head, in entaglio, infcribed sabin. and, be-

hind, a palm-branch. 
61 A fatyr teaching a young faun to play on the pipe, in en 
taglio cornelian, andaBacchus, ditto, nicolo. 
62 Bacchus and Ariadne riding on a tiger, in entaglio, jafper, 

fine work. 

63 Diana of Ephefus with her attributes, and Cupid riding on 
a dolphin, both entaglio, cornelian. 
64 A Chimera in entaglio, redjafper, and Bacchus and Ariad-
ne, in entaglio, cornelian. 

K A. 


6 5 A head of a faun, Greek work, in entaglio, cornelian ; and 
a winged Minerva, in her right hand her father&apos;s thun-
der, in her left the aegis, on her left wing fits the owl, 

infcribed p.vibit. very antient. 

66 A facrifice, with three figures, in entaglio, cornelian. 
67 Silenus and another figure facrificing, in entaglio, agate. 
68 Ifisand O ru s, before, afcarabaeus, behind, a hawk, enta 
glio, jafper, and a female bull in cameoonyx. 

69 A beautiful mafk in entaglio cornelian, and a head of Pla-

to, ditto jafper. 

7© A very fineold head in entaglio, amethyft; and aChimera, 
ditto cornelian. 

71 A Parthian king on horfeback, with Greek charafters, in 

entaglio, yellow jafper. 
72 Three warriors going to facrifice, in entaglio, jade. 

73 Night diftributing her poppies, as emblems of fleep, to the 

different inhabitants of this earth ; a child and an 

elderly man already feel the effe&amp;s, a woman begins to 
be fleepy, and fhe is giving fonte to a ftrong young 

man. A copy from one in the thirdday ; agate. 

/ f ^74 Julius Caefar, an entaglio cornelian. 

7ç Severus and Caracalla, ditto. 

76 An old foldier refting himfelf behind his fhield, ditto. 

77 A centaurwith a bow, ditto. 
78 Auguftus and Livia, ditto, blood-ftone. 

79 The head of Socrates, ditto, cornelian, very fine. 

80 The head of Vefta, white cornelian, by Wray, very 

fine. 

Marble Urns and Inficriptiom. 

81 A cinerary urn for a child, of an uncommon fhape, infcri 

bed C. TREBATIVS. FLORVS. vIxiT. ANNIS. VII. 

Aditto, very élégant, infcribed 

l. ariemo. alvpo. 

ARIENA. PROCLA. LIB. B. M.FECIT. 
Three Roman marbîeswith infcriptions. 

84 Three ditto. 
Three ditto. 
A Gieek tomb-flone to the metnory of Ares, who has deii-

vered up his armour to Mars, and given up his warfare, 
and thefe things for another world where there is only 

darknefs, in the 29Ü1 year of his âge. Over the in-

fcription is a bas-relief of two bearded figures and two 

altars : on one is placed a helmet. From the letters and 

&apos;workmanjhip, it appears to hâve bien done about the time of 

the emperor Philip. 

SJ1CONP 


SECOND DAY&apos;i SALE. 

Tue/day, June 14, 1785. 

Lot 

1 A-p^WENTYvarious unengraved ilones. 



X Fifty various antient gems. 

3 Fifty ditto. 
4 Fifty ditto. 
Fifty ditto. 
Fifty ditto. 
Fifty ditto. 

Three large cameos, and an antient cornelian ring with 
Greek charafters and hieroglyphict. 
A cornelian with Palmyrene charafters, and a bull, ««. 

doubtedly antique and very rare. 

10 Two entaglios, Domitiaand Julia Domna, antique. 

s 1 Six antique entaglios. 

Ten ditto. 
13 Fifteen ditto. 
Nine ditto, nicolo. 
15 Eleven ditto, fome with infcriptions. 

Six AEgyptian. 

Thirty-two antique entaglios, root of emerald. 
Afineheadof Galba, eut in cameo on a flint. 

Various antique Bronzes, dsV. 

19 Eleven Greek and Roman feals. 
20 Twelve antient weights, five keys, a Celt, and other anti-
quities. 

Four fibulas, a pair of nippers, two flyles, eleven fpear-

heads, and other pièces of antiquity. 
An élégant bronze figure of Time, and two boys. 
Three boys in bronze, a buft, and a pairof goats. 
24 A pair of votive feet. Venus putting on her fandal, Jupi. 

ter, and another figure. 

A fine figure of Mercury and cne of Antinous. 
A fine head of Germanicus. 
Venus rifing front the bath, and two other figures, leth 

fine and antique. 

28 An Etrufcan bronze figure, with an infeription in Etrufcan 
charadters, *very fne and rare. 

29 A bronze buft of Henry IV. of France, and one of his 

queen. 

30 A 


30 A figure, eut in black ftone, holding a fcroll with AITOAYM. 

and an antient bronze, in bas-relief, of the judge-

ment of Midas. 
31 Three antient oriental bronze cups, with filver letters and 

ornaments. 

32 Six plates of different coins, with the impreffions. 

33 Plates of different coins, with the impreffions. 
34 Two plates ofeurious Saxon coins, ditto of Englifh pattern-
pièces, ditto of antient Irifh, with the impreffions. 
3; Two plates of Samaritan coins, ditto of the Saffanides, ditto 
of Alexander the Great, and a plate of reflored coins, 

by Gallienus, with the impreffions. 
36 Five plates belonging to Dr. Kennedy&apos;s pamphlets refpe&amp;ing 
Oriuna, Carau/ïus, and Aleftus, complété. 

37 Twenty-fix plates of Syrian coins, being the complété fé 

riés, by Angel Carmey. They *were never publijhed, be 

dyingjujl as tbey &lt;were finifhed. 

38 Nineteen plates of antient Greek and Phenician coins, be 
longing to Mr. Dutens&apos; Differtations. 

39 A head modelled by Simon, three Indian divinities, two 
carvings in ivory, and two models by Albert Durer ; a 

medal in flate, and two miniatures. 

40 An oblong-fquare brafs plate, with a handle engraved with 

unknown chara&amp;ers, and feveral figures j from the late 
Dr. Mead&apos;s colle&amp;iort. 
41 Ditto. 

42 Ditto, iron, the letters and figures inlaid with gold and fil-

ver. 

Gems, fet. 
43 A large métal ring, fuppofed to hâve belonged to a coloffal 
ftatue, a malle of Kacchus, entaglio, jafper, and one 

more. 

44 Three gold rings and an antique camco. 
45 Three antique gold rings, one with an infeription, a fmall 

figure in gold, and an enamel in gold of Henry 111. of 

France, ornamented with pearl. 
46 Two cameo rings and an entaglio. 
47 A large entaglio, green jafper, engraved on both fides : on 
one, an Ave Maria; on the other, two ox herds and 

cattle. Moderno antique. 
48 A very fine peridot fet in a ring. 
A carbuncle ditto. 
A cat&apos;s-eye ditto. 
51 An onyx cat&apos;s-eye apd an avanturine. 

Three large cameos, ail fet. 

jj A large onyx cameo, two heads, a beautiful flâne. 

54 A 


A large cntaglio ingreen jafper, a bacchante, fnt work. 

55 Three cameos. 

A group of five figures in cameo, onyx. 
57 Thehead of Galba in cameo, beril. 

58 A harpy, in entaglio, fine Etrufcan work. 
Bacchus and Ariadne, in entaglio, cornelian, and one 

more. 

A beautiful malk, entaglio, cornelian. 
61 Headof Vefpafian, in cameo, onyx, &lt;very beautiful. 

62 A head of a prieft, root of emerald, and one more. 
63 TwoAEgyptian deities, entaglio, green jafper. 

An old faun playing on his pipe, in entaglio, onyx, and a 

young head of Mithridates, in entaglio, fard. 
65 A facrifice with five figures, and a bonus eventus, both in 

entaglio, cornelian. 

The râpe of Proferpine, in entaglio, cornelian, and a bo 
nus eventus, ditto. 
Two entaglio rings and one cameo. 
Head of Tigranes, in entaglio, red jafper. 
Headof Epicurus, in entaglio, root of emerald, and a ca 
meo, jacinth. 

Serapis, Diana of Ephefus, and the god Terminus, in en 

taglio, fard, and a Mars with a trophy, in ditto, cor 

nelian. 

71 Head of Hadrian, in cameo, fine onyx, and the head of 

AElius, entaglio, very fine Syrian garnet. 
A foldier viewing fome armour, and aTurk&apos;s head, both in 

entaglio, cornelian. 
Venus on a fea-horfe, attended by another fea-horfe and a 

dolphin, in entaglio, onyx. 

74 A bonus eventus, in entaglio, root of emerald, and the 
head of Omphale, in entaglio, cornelian. 
Headof Cicero, in entaglio, fard. 
76 Caftor and Pollux, in entaglio, agate. 
Julius Caefar, in entaglio, peridot, and one more. 
78 Tucia, in entaglio, Syrian garnet, -and Hercules and 

Antaeus, in entaglio, cornelian. 

79 Head of Bacchus, fine work, in entaglio, cornelian. 
80 A Roman matron, in cameo, root of emerald, and one 

more. 

Râpe of Europa, fine Greek work, in entaglio, corne 

lian. 
82 Headof Horaer, in entaglio, cornelian. 

83 Theocritus and Virgil, as the two great pafloral poets, 

with the pafloral flûte and AafF, in entaglio, onyx. 

84 Bull of Horace, in entaglio, onyx, 
fi 

8 S Tbe 



19 A bronze fragment of Hercules, very fine. 

20 A gladiator and a Mercury in bronze. 

21 Venus juft corne from the bath, and a curîous antique 

bronze with a fingular head-drefs. 
Two élégant bronze figures. 
A fine bronze head of Brutus on a ftand. 
A very fine antique marble buftof Plato on a ftand. 
Ditto of a child. 

An antique marble Roman buft. 

Ditto, a femalehead, in black marble. 
A very élégant antique fmall head of Plato in marble. 
Ditto, and the buftof a young Bacchus. 
An antique buft of an infant, in marble, very fine. 
A very fine head of Dejotarus, kingof Armenia, on a ftand. 
A very fine marble head of Pan, fine Greek vuork. 
A very fine groupe of Laocoon and his fons, in bronze, on 

a ftand. 

A young head of Hercules, a fea horfe and a griffin, and 

three fine figures, ail in ivory, the Virgin, St. John, 

and St. Lewis, and anemaciatcd old man in ebony. 

33 Two copper-plates engraved by Bartolozzi : one, the head 
of Jupiter Dodonaeus, from a gold coin of Alexander, 
(the fon of Neoptolemus,) king of Epirus ; the other, 
of Tryphon, king of Syria, from a tetradrachm in fil» 
ver of that prince. 
Twenty-eight copper plates, engraved by Bartolozzi, of 
the kings of Syria, from Mr. Duane&apos;s collection now 
in the Hunterian mufeum. 

Eight copper plates, engraved by Bartolozzi, of the kings 
of Macedon, and a coin of Alexander, fon of Neopto 
lemus, king of Epirus, with the head of Jupiter Do 

donaeus. 

38 Three cafés of models (by Benvenuto Cellini) for medals 
and coins, undoubttd originale of that grtat artiji. 

39 An enamel piClure of Louis XIV. when young, by Petti-

toe, perbaps thefineftfpecimen of tbe vuork of this célébra-

tti mafier. 

40 A moft élégant gold Roman fibula, ornamented with ena-

jnel and pearls. Tbit appears to bave bien madt about the 

âge of Confantine, and it a fuperb and matcblefe cttriofay, 

Gems, fet. 
41 Two entaglios and one cameo. 

42 Three cameos. 

43 Head of Homer in cameo, onyx. 

44 Four cameos. 

45 Two AEgyptian divinities in cameo, greenjafper. 

B 2 

46 A 


2 2 

Third Day&apos;s Sale. 

46 A canopus in entaglio, with Greek chara&amp;ers, onyx, and 
thehead of L. Verus in entaglio, cornelian. 

47 A very fine and large aqua-marine in a ring. 

48 An emblematical reprefentation of Antioch, with its attri-

butes, in entaglio, cornelian. 

49 A head of Jupiter Ammon, in entaglio, cornelian, &amp; 1 more. 
50 TVo entaglios. 
51 A king of Parthia on horfeback, with Greek charafters, 

in entaglio, green jafper. 
52 A horfe and bull, two entaglios, white and red cornelian, 

and one more. 

Venus crowning Bacchus, and Cupid teaching an old faun 

to play on the pipe, infcribed w. v.c. T. ma R. bothin 

entaglio, cornelian. 

54 The head of Auguflus in entaglio, root of emerald, and a 

vafe, ditto, cornelian. 
55 A bacchante and faun aflifting Silenus, who is drunk, in 

entaglio, agate; and the three goddeffes, Juno, Mi-

nerva, and Venus, in entaglio, cornelian. 

Hercules, when a child, kiiling the fnakes, in cameo, 
white agate, fine work, and the head of Achilles in en 

taglio, cornelian. 
A horfe galloping, in entaglio, jafper, fine voork. 

58 Night diftributing fleep to the different conditions of man-

kind, in entaglio, agate, goodvoork. 
59 A warrior with armour, in er.taglio, and an Indian Bac 

chus, in entaglio : both cornelian. 

The head of Apollo on a double cornucopia, in entaglio, 

fardonyx, and one more. 

A Roman bulla, Caftor with his horfe, in entaglio, onyx, 

1his *was found in a barrovo on Blcodmore-hill, near Pake-

fitld, in Sujfolk, in May, 1758, and engraved by Mr. 
Duane ; it is a &lt;very great curiofity, as very fevo of the 

Roman bulla are to befound even in the finefi mufeums. 

62 Head of the tragic mufe, in entaglio, fard, fine nvork. 
Diomede, with the Palladium, in entaglio, cornelian, good 

voork. 

Suppofed head of Virgil, and a maflc and harp, both in 

entaglio, cornelian. 

Head of one of the Salfanides, with chara&amp;ers, in entaglio, 

yellow jafper. 

An Egyptian deity, in entaglio, root of emerald, and a 

very élégant malk, in entaglio, onyx. 

67 A head of Brutus, in cameo, cornelian, and two entaglios. 

A bearded head, in cameo, fine onyx. 
A bearded head, cameo, fardonyx, and one more. 
AChirpera, in entaglio, red jafper, and one more, 
71 An 


Tbird Day&apos;s Sa/e. 

i3 

An abraxas, cornelian, and a boy&apos;s head, în cameo, ja-
cinth. 
A beautiful mafk, in entaglio, onyx, and one more. 
Mercury in a car drawn by four rams, in entaglio, agate, 
and a mafk, in entaglio, cornelian. 

Apollo in his chariot furrounded by the twelve figns of the 

zodiac, in entaglio, cornelian. 
A bacchanalian, in cameo, agate, and a Chimera, in en 
taglio, nicolo. 
76 Three cameos and one entaglio. 

77 A Chimera, Socrates, and a faun, in entaglio, redjafper, 

fine nuork. 

78 Bonus eventus, in entaglio, cornelian, and one more. 
79 Venus playing with Cupid, in entaglio, cornelian, and 

one more. 

A female bull, in cameo, cornelian, and one more. 

Head of Plotina, in entaglio, ruby balais, very élégant. 

A very élégant female figure, with a ltorck, in entaglio, 

nicolo. 
Three entaglios. 

A wolf devouring a flag, in entaglio, root of emerald, and 

one more. 

85 A Roman matron, in entaglio, cornelian, goodvoork. 
Head of Hercules, in entaglio, nicolo, good vucrk ; and a 

mafk, in entaglio, cornelian. 

A very fine and large icarabaeus, adorned with hierogly-

phics, in green bafaltes. 

Head of a faun, in entaglio, cornelian, good vjcrk. 

Head of Drufus, in entaglio, yellow cornelian. 
Buft of Iole, in entaglio, green jafper, goodvuork. 
91 Head of Homer, in entaglio, fard, good nuork. 

92 A female head, in entaglio, cornelian, by Birch, very fine. 

The râpe of the Sabines, in entaglio, cornelian, very fine 

*work. 

An Apollo, in entaglio, cornelian, left Greek voork. 

A buft of ayoung warrior, entaglio, beautiful fard, and of 

the beft Greek work. Tbis gem fiormerly belonged ta 
Mon/. Marriet, and is publijbed by Count Caylus. 
Bacchus and Ariadne, in entaglio, fard, beautiful vuork, by 
Marchant. 

97 An élégant rofe-wood cabinet, the upper drawers glafed. 


FOURTH D A Y*s SALE. 

Tbur/day, June 16, 1785. 
u-y 

B 

K S. 

Lot 

/; / 

/.//-

//-

&apos;7 

/ 

4-

/ 

/s 

4 

&quot; 5 

6 

L-! 

v ARIOUS catalogues of coins, printed and manu 

fcript, and forne MS. papers relating to coins. 

Various catalogues of medals, 8vo and 4to, bound in 6 

vol. 

Various foreign catalogues of coins, &amp;c. 

Mufeum Medianum, nuith thepriées. 

Catalogues of the books of Dr. Mead and Martin Folkes. 
Beauclerk&apos;s, Croft&apos;s, Afkew&apos;s, and Weft&apos;s, catalogues of 

books. 

Bibliotheca Hobbyniana, 2_tom. -^» 

Lcnd* 1769//* ^A 

? 

Se 

&lt; 

A rS 

A * 

A: 

/• 

A-

/ 

S Eight odd volumes of the Bibliotheca Harleiana. 
9 Catalogue des Livres de Monfieur L. J. Gaignot, 2 tom. 

Paris, 1769 

30 Monumenta Vetuftatis Kempiana ---

Lond. 1720 

51 Defcription des DefTeins de Monfieur Crozat 
Paris, 
Catalogue raifonné des Tableaux de Monfieur de Julienne, 
Paris, 1767 

é&gt; 

% 2 Hiftoire abrégée des Empereurs, avec une Lifte des Mé* 
dailles et la Valeur, 3 tom. 
Paris, 1767 

14 La Sciencedes Médailles, 2 tom. 
B 5 Walker on Coins and Medals -

B 3 Diftionnaire des Graveurs, par F. Bafan, 3 tom. 

&apos; &apos; 

Paris, 1767 
----• Paris, 

-j 

• *&quot; Lond. 1697 

a 6 Boze, Monfieur de. Trois DifTertations -Paris, 1705 

17 Les Règles du Deflein 

-

-Paris, c 
S 8 Specimen univerfae Rei Nummariae antiquae, a Morell 

hipf.ibçs 

39 Patin, Hiftoire des Médailles --«-

Paris, 169Ç 
20 Science des Médailles 

-Paris, 
21 Hulfii, lmp. Romanorum, Numifmata -Franc. 160$ 

22 Hildebrand, Antiquitates Romanae ---LJhraj. 1713 

il Bizot, Hiftoire métallique d&apos;Hollande --Amft. 1688 

24 Inftituzione 


JTcurtb ùay&apos;s $ait. 

I5 

Î4 ïftituzîone Ântiquario-lapidaria 

» 

-Rama, 1770 

numifmatica, a G. Ant. Monaldini, 

1772 

Relandus de Nummis vet. Hebraeorum Traj. ad Rhe. 1709 
D&apos;Arnaud de Diis IIAPEAPOIE -

Hag. Comit. 1732 

ÿ 

Hiftoire d&apos;Hercule, le Thébain ---Paris, 1758 

g Laftanofa de las Medallas Efpanolas 

Huejia, 1645 /** v 

/ 

Spizelius de Re literaria Sinenfium 
Lugd. Bat. 1660 

Lives of Spanifti Painters, tranflated from Velafco 

Lond. 1737 

Siciliae Numifmata, ç copies ----Panorm. ij6 n 

Edward and Henry Leigh&apos;s Obfervations of ail the Roma 

Emperors, illuftrated by their Coins --Land. 1664 
Oflervazioni litterarie, 5 tom. --Verona, 1737, &amp;c. 

Pierres précieufes et fines, par Monfieur Dutens 
Paris, 1776 

35 Hiftorîcal Account of Englilh Money, by Stephen Martin 

Leake ---

------Lond. 1745 

36 Obfervations on Money&gt; Bullion, and Britilh Coinage 

Lond. 1772 

37 Catalogua Numifmat. Muf. Lefroyani -Libnrn. 1763 y.*-. 

38 Hiftoire de Zénobie 
-
-
Paris, 1758 

£ 

39 An Account of a Roman Pavement lately found at Stuns-

field, by John Pointer ----Oxford, 1713 

Roman Antiquities in Britain, by Ditto -Oxford, 1724 
And the Antiquities of Arundel --

Lond. 1766 

40 Seven pamphlets relating to antiquities. 
41 Hiftoire monaftique d&apos;Irlande 

-

Paris, 1690 

42 Somner &amp; Du Frefne, Portus Jccius --Oxford, 1694 

CL U A R T O. 

43 Various quarto pamphlets. 

44 Chorea Gigantum, or an Account of Stonehenge, by Dr. 

-&gt; 

Charleton ---

-----Lond. 1663 

Narrative of finding the Crucifix and Gold Chain of St. 
Edward, by Ch. Taylor -

Lond. 1668 j; £ 

True Relation of the FaClion begun at Wifbich, by Wef-

ton, ajefuit, &amp;c. -

-----1601 

43 Letter to Dr. Mead on fome Antiquities in Berklhire, by /• é&gt; 

Fr. Wife 
-

-®--Oxford, 1738 

Conjectures on an antient Piece of Money found at Eltham, 
in Kent, by Ch. Clerke ----Lond. 1751 

46 Bayer 


J • 

49 

.A / 50 

A -51 

*&apos; *» 5* 

53 

54 





/ 

58 



60 

///-• / 61 

62 

63 
64 

&apos; 

^^65 

«.//-%66 

67 

/: ^46 Bayer de Nummis Romanis in Agro Pruflico repertis 

Lipfea, 

172* 

A &apos; 

Brenner de Regibus Armeniorum et Parthorum 
Stockholm, 1723 C* 
Appendicula ad Numifmata Graeca, a Comit. Chriftiano 

Vienna, 1769 

47 AEneasVicus,-and two more. 

48 Hiiloire des Rois de Thrace, par Cary 

-

Paris, 1752 

Numifmatum Antiquorum Sylloge, ex Cimeliarchio Dn. 

Wren 

-
---Lond. 1708 

Explication de quelques Médailles, par Monfieur L. Du-

tens -----» 
-Lond. 1774 

Catalogus Nummorum Sueo-Gothicorum in Mufeo Grain-

ĝeri 

ano, a Nie. Kedero 

--Lond. 1728 &apos; 

Two Placarts, bound in one. 

De Caefare defignato SuccelTore Commentarius, a G. L. -

/ 

Hausfriz --
--

» Norimb. 1737 

De Ciftophoris, a A. Xaverio 
-Lugd. 1734 
Numifmata maximi Moduli, e Mufeo Fr. de Camps 

Paris, 1695 

I Difcorfl del Sen. D. Ant. Agoftini fopra le Medaglie, -

MSS. 

Lettere fopra alcune antiche Infcrizione di Sert. Orfato, a 
Bapt. Nani 

-

-

--

-Padoua, 1659 
Sigel. Havercampi Diflertationes de Alexandri Magni Nu-
mifmate, et de Nummis contorniatis -Ludg. 172a 

Joh. Macarii Abraxas,-and five more. 

/&gt;/4* &amp;c--

Differtatio de Nummis non eufis, a Ott. Sperlingio 

Amji. 1700 

Hiftoire des Rois de Thrace, par Monfieur Cary 

Paris, 1752 

Moneta di Friula, di Giang. Liruti 

Ventx. 1749 
X 

Mifcellanea Numifmatica, a P. D. Magnan, 4 tom. 
Romte, 1772, &amp;c. 
Les Céfars, de l&apos;Empereur Julien, par le Baron de Span-
heim 

----

-

Amjl. 1728 
Chiflet de Othonibus AEreis, &amp;c. ----Antnu. 1656 
Cafp. Wefer de antiquis Nummis Hebraeorum, &amp;c. 
Tigur. 1605 
Tacobi de Bie Numifmata aurea, a Sig. Havercamp. 

* 

AmJl. 1738 4, -Medal 

s, Coins, great Seals, &amp;c. of T. Simon, by G. / » 

Virtue 

--

-Lond. 1753 . 

Phil. Argelatus de Monetis ltaliae, 4 tom. 
Mediol. 1750, &amp;c. 

68 Gorà 


Fourth Day* s Sale. 

68 
69 

70 

7 1 

U A/-/ 72 

&gt;-^74 

Gori il Fiorino d&apos;Oro antico 

-Firenze, 1 7 3 8 
Dialogos de las Medallas, Ant. Augultino, por Man. Sebalt. 

de la Quadra -

-* Madrid, 1744 

Ditto, tradotti nella Lingua Italiana 

Roma, 1592 

Congeturas fobre las Medallas de los Reyes Godos, por 

DonL. J. Velafquez 

Annales de Efpanola, por Don 
Malaga, 17 5 9 

^75 

. 

2&gt; *-76 
77 

/ 

79 
iu~C 
• L *&apos;» 

80 

82 
83 
84 

7 

* 

1t L 

f 85 

86 

i.V^-87 
• &gt; *&apos; l 88 

89 



9* 



93 

• 



^95 

97 

L. J. Velafquez 

Malaga, 17 59 

Obelifchi &amp; Colonni di Roma --• --
Roma, 165! 
Recueil des Médailles, par Monfieur Pelleiin, avec toutes 
les Suppléments, complet, en 10 tom. Paris, 1762, &amp;c. 
Obfervations fur quelques Médailles de Monfieur Pellerin, 
par l&apos;Abbé le Blond 

-

--Paris, 1771 
Explication de quelques Médailles Grecques et Phéni 

ciennes, par Monfieur L. Dutens --Lond. 1773 
Ditto, avec Additions 

-

-Lond. 1776 

Numifmata Imperatorum Romanorum praeftantiora, a Jo-

ann. Vaillant, 3 tom. ---

-Roma, &gt;743 

Supplementum ad Numifmata praeüantiora Vaillantii, a 
Jof. Khell 

-

-Vindob. 1767 
Ĥaym, 
Teforo Britannico, 2 vol. 

-

-

Lond. 1719D 

itto 

-Lond. 1719_ 

Ditto, gr.pap. cum NotisMSS. Cl. J. Maflon Lond. 1719 _ 

FJorez Medallas d&apos;Efpana, 2 vol. gr.pap. -Mad. 1757 _ 
Theupoli Numifmata antiqua, 2 tom. --Venet 1736-

Contemplatio Gemmarum etCranae Infula, a Laur. Beger 
Brand. 1696 
Nummi veteres Anecdoti, a Jof. Eckhell -Vienn. 1775 
De Wilde Numifmata antiqua 

-Amjlel. 1692 

Ad Numifm. Regum veterum Acceflio nova, ab Erafmo 

Froelich 

Vienn. 

Diflertationes variae, a Joanne Swinton Oxford, 17^0, &amp;c. 

Offervazione iftoriche ïopra alcuni Medaglioni antichi di 

Granduca 

-

&apos; 

• • 

Roma, 1698 

Ditto. 

Seledta Numifmata ex Mufeo Seguini --Lut et. 1684 

Thelaurus Numifmatum ex Mufeo Patini &apos; --1672 

Conft. Landi Numifmata feleftioria ---Lugd. 1695 

Alius. 

Erafm. Froelich, Notitia Elementaris Numifmatum 

Vienn» 1758 

Quatuor Tentamina in Re Numaria 

Vienn. 1750 

Edw. Corfini Differtatio de Nummo Minifari Regis, &amp;c. 

Roma, 1757 

C 

98 Lud. 

/ 

ta t&gt; 

é&gt; 

f 

&amp; 

/ 

/f--

/£ 

. 

/z--* 

r. 

/â • &amp; 

/ 0 / 

/é *» 

/ -

Y? -


ï8 

Fourth Day&apos;s Sale, 

98 Lud. Smids de duodecem Imperatorum Nummis Amjl. 1699 

9g Marq. Freheri Diflertatio de Numifmate -Heidelb. 1699 

Pétri Burmanni Jupiter Fulgerator in Nummis Cyrrhefta-
rum, et alia, 3 bound in cne --

Trajeft. 1700 
Gronovius de Seftertiis,-and two more. 

101 Car. Patin de Numifmatibus quibufdam lmp. Neronis 

Brem. 1681 

Punet. de Coloniae Tarraconae Nummo -&apos;Tigur. 174S 

Infignia Numifmata Imperatorum veter. Romanorum. 

êO^A nd. Morellius de Nummis Confularibus -Amji. 1701 

Ever. Otto de Servio Sulpicio Rufo 

Trajeél. 1725 

Henr. Noris Diflertatio de duobus Nummis Dioclefiani 

etLicinii, 3 bound iu one » 

Flor. 1675 
Numifmata antiqua Com. Pembrochiae, 2 tom. 

Lond. 1746 

Nummi veter. Populorum et Urb. a Mufeo Doft. Hunter, 

Lond. 1782 

Ditto. 
Ditto. 
Ditto. 

Henr. Noris Epochae Syro-Macedonum -Florent. 1689 
111 Lawr. Paterol Opéra omnia, 2 tom. ---Venet. 1743 

Hanthaler de Nummis, 2 tom. 

-Vindob. 1756 

3 Phil. A. Furre de Annis Imperii M. Aur. ant. Elagabali 
Bat av. 1713 

Vigniolii de Anno primo Alexandri Severi Roma, 1714 
15 L. Savct, Difcours fur les Médailles 

Paris,. 1627 

116 Mifcellanea varia Antiqua et Numifmatica -1676, &amp;c. 

Eleéla Rei Nummariae 

---Hamb. 1709 
Alius. 
J. F. Vaillant Hiftoria Regum Syriae 
-Lutet. 1681 
Jac. Oifelius, Numifmata antiqua 
Amft. 1677 
De Bie Numifmata aurea Imperat. Romanorum 
Ant. 1627 

122 Hiftoire de l&apos;Académie des Infcriptions et Belles Lettes, 

37 tom. 

--
Paris, 1736,&amp;c. 

123 Rowland&apos;s Mona antiqua -

&gt; 

Lond. 1766 

124 Roma antiqua Nardini 

Roma, 1704 

Rofini Romanae Antiquitates 
Amjl. 1685 
125 Fr. Ficoroni Veftigia et Rarita di Roma anticha 

Roma, 1744 

126 Wogen Alterthumer der Obotriten 
Berlin, 1771 

127 Montfaucon, Diarium Italicum 

-Paris, 1702 

u8 Manr.ora Arundeliana. 

129 Infcriptione3 


U 

\ 

Fi/th Day&apos;s Sale. 

129 Infcriptiones P.eginae 

130 Corfini Falli Attici, 2 torn. 

Neapol. 1770 

F/or. 1744 

F I F T H D A Y&apos;s SALE. 

Friday, J une 17, 1785. 

i. o /f J 

Lot 

13 D ICTIONNAIRE 

Salzade 

des Monnoies, par Monfieur de 

132 Ben. Floravanti Denarii Pontif. Romanorum Roma, 1734 

133 Orfini délia Monete Fiorentina, 2 tom. -Firenxe, 1760 
154 Venuti Numifmata praeft. Pontif. Romanorum Roma, 1744 

-135 Brenner Nummi Sueo-Gothici 

-Holm, 

136 Virtue&apos;s Medals, Coins, Seals, &amp;c. of J. Simons 

Lond. /. 

: -137 Martin Folkes on Englilh Coins ---Lond. 
138 Clarke on Coins 

---» 

« 

Lond. 

139 Pettingal and Pegge&apos;s Trafts 

A-

//a,-

Lond. 1763, &amp;c. 

Lond. 

141 R yal and Withey&apos;s plates of Englilh coins 

Lond. \ 756 

142 Ditto. 

143 L. Agoftini Gemme antiche, 2 tom. --Roma, 

144 Pierres gravées du Baron de Stoch, par l&apos;Abbé Winckel-

mann 

--
--. -Flor. 

Livorni, 

-Paris, 

Lond. 
Padoua, 

2 tom. 
Napol. 

150 Origine des anciens Peuples, par Monfieur Fourmont, 2 
tom. 

-

Paris, 

151 NeroCaefar, dedicated to the Duke of Buckingham 

Lond. 1627 
152 Various tra&amp;s. 
153 Abecedario pittorico 

----Neap. 1783 
*-154 Rie. Chandler&apos;s Travels into Afia Minor -Lond. 

* 

155 Niebuhr, Description de l&apos;Arabie 

«» 

Amji. 1774 

C 2 

156 Nicolfon 

140 Pegge on the Coins of Cunobeline -

145 De gli Intagliatori 

-

146 L&apos;Antiquité des Tems 

i/j.7 Con. Middleton Monumenta antiqua 
-

148 Marini Eruditi, a Sert. Orfato ---
149 Antichita d&apos;Ercolano, di Oit. Ont. Bayardi, 

/y. 

/ 

/&gt; -

. 

&amp; 

/9 L 

/ y» &apos; 

M 

1 * 

/Ü-


/. f. -156 Nicolfon and Burn, Hiftory and Antiquities of the 

Counties of Weltmoreland and Cumberland, 2 vol. 

/ / 

Lond. 1777 

/. / 

3 ç7 Anecdotes of Britifh Topography 

//-/ &apos; 

/•/-*• 

/. /y -

158 Caltndars of Welfh and Scottîlh Rolls 

159 Strut&apos;s Chrcnide, z vol 

Lond. 1768 

Lond. 1772 ^7&quot; 1 

iw. 1777 Cgt&apos;£&apos;\ 

a : * 

J?.-//-* 

.£&apos;• /a. a 

160 Strut on the Manners, Cultoms, &amp;c. of the Saxons and c / V&gt;« 

Englilh, 3 vol. 

-Lond. 1774, 

161 
Gibfon&apos;s Chronicon Saxonicam 

-Oxford, 1692 âf £ 

162 Philofophical Tranfadions, 18 odd volumes, and the f . x 3 

Statutesof the Royal Society. 

. 

163 Archaeologia, 5 vol. 

-

1770» &amp;c. 

1C4 Bibliotheca topographica Britannica, No. I. to XIX. in-

clufive, and No. XXIII. and XXIV. Lond. 1780, &amp;c. 

165 Bibliotheca literaria, ten numbers 

Lond. 1722 

166 Jac. Na-fmith, Catalog. Libr. MSS. Coll. C. C. Cantab. 

Cant. J 777 
167 Bibliotheca Smithiana 
--

Venet. 1759 

168 Paleografia Efpanola, por Eft. de Terreros Madrid, 1758 

169 A critical Eflay on Oil-Painting, by E. Rafpe Lond. 1781 

170 Remains of Japhet, by J. Parfons -

-

Lond. 1767 

171 Ditto. 

172 Wicquefort, l&apos;Ambafladeur et fes Fonctions, 2 tom. 

Haye, 1É82 

/A-î/&apos;* 

f /ad* 

A *&apos; -

/ * -

FOLIO. 

173 Veterum llluftrium Imagines, a Bellorio -Rcma, 1685 
174 Joann. Jac. Luckius, Numifmata ---Argent. 1620 

175 J. Evelyn on Medals 

« 

-Lond. 1697. 

L 

176 T. Snelling&apos;s Englifli Medals 

-

-Lond. 1776 

177 T. Snelling&apos;s View of Englifh Coins, ail the Parts 
, , 

Lond. 1762/^* ^,at * 
178 J. F. Vaillant, Numifm. Imperat. Graeca, cum multis Ad-

ditionibus 

--&gt; -

-. --Am/l. 1700 

ĵ 

79 J. F. Vaillant, Nummi Fam. Roman.. 2 tom. Am/l. 1703 ,, 

180 J. F. Vaillant, Numifm. Imperatorum in Coloniis cufa *&apos;&quot;/* &apos; 

Paris, 1688 

A-

Hag. 1732 
Amjl. 1701 

S 

181 J. F. Vailliant, Hiftoria Regum Syriae -
182 J. F. Vaillant, Hiftoria Ptolemaeorum -

^183 

Car. Patin, Numifm. Imperat. Romanor. -Paris, 1696^/ft-ru -

184 

Fainiliae Romanae • 

-Paris, 1663 

185 L. Beger, Thefaurus Palatinus -

-Heideb. 1685 
ï86 L. Beger, Spicilegium Antiquitatis --Bratid. 1692 

*8; Trillan, Commentaires hiftoriques, 3 tom. Paris, 1644 

188 Nutu-


V £-ts &apos; 

d &apos; &apos; 

j Sc~/* &lt;£ 

188 

189 
190 

7S 19* 

192 

y/c«Ü93 

&gt;^«9+ 
*//*-SU A-195 

&lt;* 

196 
197 

-198 

&gt; 

*99 

* v ^200 

/* 

*/-? 4&quot;-20I 

4 ^202 




205 

20t» 

207 



2 10 

Nummophyladum Reginae Chrillinae, a S. Havercamp 
/fag. 1742 &lt;. 

Â. 

Banduri Numifmata, 2 tom. 
£«/. 17iS 

Fr. Wife de Nummis Bodleianis 

Oxf.ijço&apos; &apos;&apos; 

Mufellii Numifm. antiqua, 3 tom. in z -Vtron. 1751 / Z&apos; .*/ 

L. Beger, Regum et lmperatorum Numifmata 

Brand. 1700 

J. J. Gefner, Numifmata, 3 tom. --Tigur. 1738 *A ^** 

Sig. Morellianus, Thelaurus Famil. Roman. 2 vol. 

Amft. 1734 / 

--

--» 

-&quot; 

Imperator. Roman. 3 vol. 
Amft. 1752 */&quot;•&apos; 

La Siciliadi Paruta, con Medaglie 

-

Rorna, 1699 

Ditto 
-----
---

Lion. &gt;697 

Hub. Goltzii Opéra omnia, ç tom. 
Antv. 1645 9, : 

Hon. Aregoni Numifmata, 3 tom. -Taras. 1741, Scc. /&gt; 

Numifmata AErea maximi Moduli e Mufeo Pifano, 2* 

tom. 

-

1 

-1740$ / 

Wood&apos;s Athenae Oxonienfes, 2vo&apos;. 

-1720 /-• 
Geo. Hicks, Thefaurus Linguarum vet. Septent. 2 tom. 

Oxford, 1705 J 

. 

F,dw. Lhuyd, Archaeologia Britannica -Oxford, 1707 

J. Spelman, Vita AElfredi Magni 
-Oxf. 1678 
J. Harduini Opéra leledla 
|. Harduini Opéra varia 

&gt;7/ 

/&gt;. d 

9 ; c? 

/.*• J 

Amft. 1719 

A™ft&apos; «733 

Neafi. 1754 

Venet. lt&gt;8i 
Flor. 1727 

/ ^u 2 I « 

2 I 2 

/ 

2 i 

0 
L* 

J 

&apos;f. 

2, 5 

216 
217 
218 
219 

220 

221 

r 

Al. Sym. Mazochii Antiq. Heraclienfes -
F. H. Noris, Cenotaphia Pifana 

-

Ant. Fr. Gorii Monumentum Liviae Auguftae 

Plates belonging to Molinet&apos;s Cabinet de Ste. Geneviève, 
complété --

----1688 
Salluilio en Efpanol, edit. rar. &amp; élégant. Madrid, 1772 é : /d-.d 

Stepbanus de Urbibus --~--
Amft. 1725 

Antiche iferizione di Palermo ----Palermo, 1762 /-• 
Traité des Pierres gravées, par P. J. Mariette, 2 tom. 

Paris, 1750 /.* f 

L. Natter on the antient Method of engravine piecious 

Stones 

--

* 

Lond. 1754 
Mufeutn Cortonenfe 

--Roma, 1750 J&apos; &apos; * 

G. P. Bellori, Antiche Lucerne fepolchrali 

Roma, 1691 

Al. Gordon, Itinerarium Septentrionale -Lond. 1726 

A Cat may look at a King, by Sir Antony Welding, MS. 

1 

avril ten 1652 
Wolff. Lszio, Hiftoria Graeca 

-Hanoas. 16J5 

Plutarch&apos;s Lives, tranflated by Sir Thomas North 

Lond. 1681 


/. 

^4 

22 

222 

2 23 

224 

J 225 

I 

. 

&apos; • // : 0 

/: //&apos; 

1 */a ; 

/ * 

Fifth Day&apos;s Sale. 

J. P. Bellorius in xii. Caefarum Numifmata Roma, 1730 

Médailles de Louis le Grand 

Paris, i6gt 

Du Molinet, Numifmata Pontificum 
-Lutet. 1679 

7.* 

226 


228 

229 



231 







237 

239 
240 

24 I 

Biblia Hebraica, a Benjamin Kennicotr, vol. I. 

Oxford 

t 

1776 

John Richardfon&apos;s Perfiar» and Arabie Diétionary, 2 vol. 

,7 

Oxford, 1777 L 
Merveilles de Fontainebleau 

.----Paris, 1642, 

Cl. Menetreio, Symbolica Dianae Ephefiae Statua 

Roma, 1688 

Siciliae veterum Infcriptionum Colleélio nova 

Panorm. 1769 

Dorville Sicula -

•a&gt;/£-

Spanhemii Numifmata, 2 tom. 

-

Gori Thefaurus Gemmarum, 3 tom. --

--Mufeum Etrufcum, 3 tom. 

• 

Amft. 1764 

Lond. 

1706^y ot-, e/*&apos; 

Lond. 1706 

F/or. 1750 f£&gt;:,+. ot-
Flor. 1737 J-y 
T. Malton&apos;s Treatife on Perfpeétive, complété. 

La Gerufalemme di Torquato • ---Genoua, 1617 

Ware&apos;s Antiquities of Ireland, by Harris 

Dublin, 1764 

Hon. Arigoni Numifmata Antiq. 3 Tom. Tarv. 1741, &amp;c. 

Stradae Numifmata 

&lt; 

-

-Franc. 1629 
Angeloni Hiftoria augufta 
-Roma, 1641 
A volume of plates of impérial coins, intended for a 
book which was never publilhed, &lt;very fcarce. 
Anf. Banduri Imperium Orientale, 2 tom. 
Paris, 

Afhmole&apos;s Order of the Garter 

« 

1672 
Journal de Palais 

» 

-

Paris, 1713 

à 242 

243 
244 

.... 

,245 A MSS. Catalogue of antient Coins, with drawings. 

THE END. </unit>


<other>gga 

|OW 

H(C N£K)HH4V-otaKE*°H KlX^NMpr 

jqQÏgN^S^^Hfflî^XjKHaN* 

t£K3b64ilX&lt;HK^HXC HP&lt;H}RCÇXO&lt;*t 
5£HOEHOEaH)«»5lc»ipoeKMXĉ 

W4&amp;B4Ko£M M WXo«M£raH&gt; 

gfflBaagas^r 

rrt .. r1l 

sa&amp;îssfesaas»« 

&gt;&lt;*-01 

iSS tofeiofcj 

OE 

ffbthOKW I 


I-•; ,V\î: 

\\whH 

&gt; * 

•wv 

1 

F* 

.1 #?.-&gt;. 

, 

t-f 

-

&apos;&quot;&apos;M 

• 

&apos; &apos; &apos; &gt; 

• 

? 

V 

&apos; 

-

V 

. 

*S 

T 

-

» 

I «T* ; , V,-% 

• 

, 

,/ 

, 

-V 

.«4£* •.. 

, 

-

* 

&gt; 

* •&apos; 

. 

. 

, • 

-

. 

* 

, 

&apos; 

: 

&apos; &apos; 

; 

-

-

* 

; -

I 

&apos; 

. 

IÎA ï 

. 

m 

. 

i «T*~-&apos;V ; &apos; -• •:* 

* 

*•* 

» VV,. 

: 

• 

• 

jf 

• 

ï&quot;. ; &apos; 

; 

* 

&apos;ï 

&apos; 

*. 

«&lt;-»&apos; ; ~v 

J * 

•-&apos;• 

&apos; -f:&apos; : 

4 

&apos; ? U-

. 

Il 

&apos; i. 

:» 

• 

&quot; t 

.&apos;JOEm 


jN9AMMC4H0&gt;r^MMO|MX*4Ol4^| 

QRHe^KRlONQNÔMéjodm 

k&gt; rp 99 •&lt; hx 04 otp mrc# 

H)H;nHU*Xtta.»**O4mt0 

*«Hnij*«kci m I hHcha 

»s%Wïaev. 

3&lt;X «IU****«M*«aw&lt;u ir 

msessm 

NK 

2S«NNW 








\ </other>








</text>
</tei>