<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">



<title>r.cmr.T 190? 






|ioJO&lt; r Jk% 

CATALOGUE 

OF THE LARGE&apos; 

COLLECTION 

O F 

SILVER and COPPER 

COINS and MEDALS, 

formed by 

Dodor Phillips, 

CONSIST I NG 

OfGreek, Roman,English, Irish, Scotch* 

Italian, German and French; 

Moft of which are in fine Prefer vation : 

ALSO, 
Several curious CABINETS, a LIBRARY 

chiefly relating to Antiquities; fome Manufcripts* 
feveral Port Folios of Prints, Maps, &amp;c. an 
Oriental Sword and Creece, &amp;c. 

Which will be fold by AUCTION, 

By Mr. Langford and Son, 

At their Houfe in the Great Piazza, Ccver.t 

-

Garden, 

On P&apos;hurfday the 16th of July 1772, and the two 

following Days. 

The fame may be viewed onTuefday the 14th Infiant, and till the 
Time of Sale, whit;h will begin each Day pundlually at 
Twelve o&apos;fc&apos;lock. 

Catalogues of which maybe had gratis on the Days of 
Viewing, and at Mefi&quot;. Langford&apos;s aforefaid. </title>


<preface>Conditions of SALE. 

iy?, rp H E higheft Bidder is to be the Buyers 

and if any Difpute fhall arife between 
any two or more Bidders, the Lot fo difputed fhall 

be immediately put up again, and refold. 

idly-t No Perfon to advance lefs than 6d. under a 

Pound; above a Pound is; above Five Pounds 

ts 6d. and fo on in Proportion. 
gdly, The Purchafers are to give in their Names 
and Places of Abode, and to pay down Five Shillings 

in the Pound (if required) in Part of Payment of 

the Purchafe Money; in Default of which, the 

Lot or Lots fo purchased, to be immediately put up 

again and refold. 

/ythly, The Lots fhall be fetched away with 

all Faults, at the Buyer&apos;s Expence, within One 

Day after the Sale 

, 

and the Remainder of the 

Purchafe Money absolutely paid on or before 

the Delivery. 

Laftly, Upon Failure of complying with the above 

Conditions, the Money fo depofited in Part of Pay 

ment 

^fnall be forfeited\ the Lots uncleared within the 

One Day as aforefaid, fhall be refold, by publick 

or private Sale, and the Deficiency (if any) together 

with all Charges attending fuch Refale, fhall be made 

good by the Defaulters at this Sale* </preface>


<unit>1J. .4 0 


[ 4 J 

D&lt; 

£ 
| S Small Greek towns and families 

-----

f.fit&apos;0 19 Two Athenae, 3 Phillip, Alexander Magnus, Anti-

ochus Evergetes, Corintn and another 
-

*5 

V 7 

BRITISH, SAXON and ENGLISH COINS 

/./# O 20 Cunobeline, and 5 other Eritifh, rare 

f, /J 

&apos; * 21 Athelftaq, and 4 others 

&apos;,1 z-7 ,1 2 2 CoelwufF, Edgar* Ethelred, Cnut, &apos;very rare 

7 -/ * 

2&quot;? Edward C-Sar.&amp;i Petri Moneta, &amp; Harold, with /ax 

0* /7-

^J 

/; • 0 

on the reverfe, very fine 

j&gt;. n* V 24 William I. Will. II. Henry I. and Stephen 

-

^25 Henry I. Rich. t. John, Henry III. 

---

. 

/ 2b Edward I. II. and III. pence, halfpence and far-

0&apos; &apos; &apos; 

^things 

)*)&amp; 2 7 Edward III. groat, half groat, penny, halfpenny and 

&apos; 

farthing-* Rich. II. penny, halfpenny, and far 

thing and groat 

0*2 

. 

uiuj^auu 

-; 

-

[1 

28 Henry IV. great, half groat, penny, halfpenny, and 

farthing 

/ (29 Henry V. ditto 

_ 

0-4 w (3°H enry VI. ditto 

-

C 7 0 -1 1 Richard III. groat, * very f carce coltf 

7 *7 32 Henry VII. groat, Jtalf groat, 2 pennies, an half-

I&apos; v 

penny and farthing. 

-2 6 33 Henry VIII. groat, &apos; 4 half groats 

34 Edward VI. crown, .talf crown, drilling, and fix-

pence 

O-/2.0 

x~t y 35 Philip and Mary&apos;s drilling and ftx-pence, a three-

pence of Mary&apos;s, and a Elander&apos;s medal of 

Philip 

* 

-

/ J J&gt; 0 36 Queen Eliz. crown, half crown, 2 (hillings, 10 dx-

pences, 4 (hillings, 7 fix-pences, 

1 

clipped, 
q groats, 11 three-penccs, 5 two-pences, 6 pen 
nies, 3 halfpence, and 3 farthings 

0 //• 0 37 Janies&apos;s crown, half crown, 2 drillings, and fix-

pencp 

---

/7 

^38 Charles I. 20 (hilling piece, 10 drillings, 2 crowns, 
•5&apos;Q* 

anchor half crown, anchor ihiiling and fix-pence, 
feaiher fix pence and four-pence, Briot&apos;s two 
pence, pothers, and 4 pennies 

/2*0 39 Ccrnmon wealth cro vn, half crown, (hilling, dx-

pence, two-penc£, penny, and halfpenny 

, 

/ ^,4.0 Oliver&apos;s crown, half crown and drilling, the firJi ex-

&apos; 

tani for preftrvati* a 

3 

&apos;^r{4 
&gt; rl&apos;Y 

9&apos;^/ 

g 

rr» 

5 If 

7 / 

5 6 

If st-u-&apos;i-iq 

v 7 

/&apos; JO. 

Newark half crown, (hilling, nine pence and fix-

J &apos; 

&apos; 

p&lt; nee ; Pontefrad* ihiiling; Madachufet&apos;s drilling 

a .4 t:.rce-pcnce 

\t L 

&apos; 
42 Charles 

7 

S / 

7 

^y A 


yjrftw/-4 2 

V 

43 

^744 

y45 

4 6 

t 5 1 

Charles II. crown, half crown, {hilling, fix-pence, 

four-pence, two pence and penny 

James II crown, half crown, {hilling, four-pence, 

three-pence, two-pence and penny 
-

William and Mary&apos;s crown, half crown, {hilling, 

four, pence, three-pence, two-pence and penny 

K : ng William&apos;s crown, half crown, {hilling, fix-

pence, four-pence, three-pence; two pence, and 
penny 

-

Queen Ann&apos;s crown, half crown, {hilling, fix pence, 

four pence, three pence, two pence and penny 

Vigo crown, half crown and {hilling; Exeter crown, 
half crown and fnilling 

Geoige I. crown, half crown, {hilling, fix pe&gt; ce, 

and a penny George III {hilling, four pence and 

three pence 

/ff 

8 

49 Geoige II. crown, half crown, {hilling, fix-pence, 

^four-pence, three-pence, two pence and penny 

8 

0. /3-N 

0 .l/i-o 

0-fV-o 

€ 11*0 

C 

/. f&amp;.o 
c.i3 &amp; 

/ 

50 

* 

5 1 

f fj/n* * &apos;75 2 

SILVER ENGLISH MEDALS. 

Armada medal, marriage medal of Henry Prince of 

Orange, at London 1641 

-

Charles I. and his Queen, and a medal on Charles&apos;s 

return to the city 1633, by Briot 

-

Oliver, pax queriter btllo, and Dacier&apos;s funeral medal 

of Oliver 

-

Oliver, Non deficient Oliva, and the fmall one 

Earl of Effex, rare 

-

Fairfax, fcarce 

•• • 

Dunbar medal 

-

-

2 / 

O. 

0 

2 

f 

c 

O 

12&apos; c 

y • 6 

/5 6 

Do 

-(o o 

7o 

&lt;/2 6 

ROMAN BRASS. 

Roman middle brafs, from Caefar to Pollhumus 

4°-

_o n 

T.-1: 

hi 

/ &apos; ^• 

-

------

c 58 From Julius to Conftantine, genuine medals, highly 

preferred and feme of them extremely rare 
40 0 

59 Lower Empire 40, and fmall brafs 85* two drawers, 

in 1 lot 

--

. 

125 0 

0*0 

/O&apos; 

7 

LARGE 


67 Large Plan of London, Plan of York, Plan cf Briftol, Plan 

of Gibraltar, Citadel of Plymouth, Survey of Wilton 

Houfe, Gardens and Park, View of Twickenham, 

Elphinfton&apos;s Map of Great Britain and Ireland 1746, 
and Map of Suffolk 
68 Plan of Dunkirk, Brclt and Toulon, large Map of France, 
fmall Carte de France, large Map of the Empire of 
Germany ; Roy&apos;s Plan of the Battle of 1 linden, with 
a Relation of it, and Jour, a! of the Army, palled 

on Canvas, and dedicated to Prince Ferdinand-The 

Arms of the Nobility of England, Scotland and Ire 

land, blazoned 

BOOKS, 


books. 

OCTAVOS Infra. 

69 Hiftoire Mctallique de Hollande, Tom. 3. par Bizot 
Amji. 168S 

70 Sandby&apos;s Virgil, 2 vol. 

71 Cornelius Agrippa&apos;s, Bafil Valentine&apos;s and Spon&apos;s Voy 
age to Italy and Greece, 2 vol. 

*71 Leake on Coins, Revenue of the Romans, Meditations 
of Antoninus Pius, and Lives of the Reman Em-

prefles 

72 Scipio&apos;s Maffei&apos;s Hiftory of Amphitheatres, Antiquities of 
Conftantinople, Defcription of Weftmir.fter Bridge, 
Wilton, Stow, Blenheim, Ditchley, &amp;c. 
73 Defcription of Weflminfter Abbey, St. Paul&apos;s, Tower, &amp;c» 
-Pliftory of York-Polymetis abridged, and Chroni-

con Pretiofum 

74 Macaulay&apos;s Short Hand-MemoriaTechnica -Hoppus&apos;s 

Meafuring 

75 The Life and Death of the blefied Virgin, and feveral 
Tradts of Dr. Claget&apos;s 
76 Lives of Dr. Boerhaave, Cheyne, Ratcliife, and Grea-
treakes, and Life of General Monk 

QUARTO. 

77 Harm&apos;s Teforo Britannico, Italian and Englilh-How-

grave&apos;s Hiftory of Stamford ---Hayes&apos;s Method of 

valuing Annuities 

78 Vaillant Numifmata, 2 tom. «=-»«--L&apos;lmagini de gli An 

tichi del Signor Vinzenzo Venetia 1625 
Nicolai 

Tradtatus de Siglis Veterum 

79 Brenneri Thefaurus Nummorum Sueco Gothicorum --

De Bie Numifmata Romanorum --Gorlaei Annu-

lorum Sigillarium 

F 0 L I O. 

Io Meneftrier&apos;s Medallic Hiftory of Louis le Grand-Symbol* 

Pontificum Imperatorum Regum 

-La France MetaU 
lique, par J. De Bie 

81 Goltzii 



[ 9 J 

dffetx /&apos; &lt;? 4 A full Alite of James the lid&apos;s brafs money, viz. 
4 crowns, horfemen, i o half crowns, I2lhiliings, 

ff/&apos; 

and 4 fix-pences 

$6 C S&apos; 

&gt;//a. x^r 5 Nirte uncommon foreign medals 

^c //, 

Complimentary medals in the reign of Lewis XIV. 
and acteflion one of Lewis XV. finelyJlruck 

33 /. /-O 

The kings of En gland from William I. to Geo. III. 
and i of William, Duke of Cumberland, by 

Ddcier 

• 

36 «3&gt; 

8 Sir Ilaac Newton, Mr. Locke, Shakefpear, Lord Ba 

con, Dr. S. Clarke, Archbifhop Wake, Inno. II. 

Benedict XIV. and 3 cf Mary, Queen Anne and 

her hulband on the reverfe 

9 One large and 3 ftnall medals of George II Peter 

the Great, King of Sardinia, Prince of Orange, 
his father the late prince. King of Denmark, 
King of Poland, A cujujl efl, and 2 honorary 

medals 

. 

C 

M&apos;O 

-

12 C It) 4&gt; 

3r 

i /• /• 0 

SILVER MEDALS. 

1-0 Carolus II. reverfe Catharina Regina, reftoration me 

dal, and coronation medal ; large medal,fa-ventt 

Deo; Ditto, pro talibus aufs ; medallion, Auguft. 

Carolo, injcnpto nullum /rumen abejf, Charles and 

Cath. reverfe, dijfus in or be Brit anna, 1670 

Inftallation medal of Charles II. of Sweden, and the 

7 bifhops 

On the Prince of Orange&apos;s lahding at Torbay, Dutch 

medal on the revolution, Another, Gaels delabi-

ier alto, uEre perennis ; Coronation meCal of Wil 

liam and Mary, reverie, Pretium &amp; Cauja Lalorir, 

Ditto, a coronation call, u April 1689, and Bri 

tannia Supphx 1693 

-) 

0 *1 b&apos;°A 

n acceffion medal of Queen Anne&apos;s^fmall Coro 

nation, on the taking the galleons at Vigo, on the 

battle of Blenheim, on the taking of Barcelona, 
on the invafion in Scot and 1708, battle of 

Tournay, on the Peace 1713 
-
14 Medallion of Qpeen Anne, giving the firft fruits to 

the clergy 171c, cn the union, Oudenard, Te 
niers, Sardinia and Minorca; Saragoifa 1710, 
Dcway 1710, Gibraltar 

• 

/ 

; 

I5 Box medal on the battle of Blenheim, of block tin, 

&apos;ff yev-yve] exquifitely well fruck, and containingJeveral repre-

fentations of the Duke of Marlborough, from a cor 

poral to a gensralijfmo ; Another, on the fame nit-

B 

tal, 

.SB* 

/ 

8 /•/*•&apos; 

S3L, 

.// 

0 -
5-b 



[ &gt;« ] 

LARGE BRASS. 

3°3 
&apos; 

32 

.6 

The firft twelve Csefars, well preferred 

12 £&apos;&gt; 

Roman emprefles 16, Middle brafs ot the Auguftan 
age 10, one Imperial, and 13 Roman Egyptian 

coins 

-. ....... 

40 / 

• 3 

Middle brafs from Csefar to Tiehonius Decius, msf. of 

them genuine medals, ojery rare, and in great preferva-
tion 

Greek, Phenician and Egyptian. 

33 Antiochus, Epiphanes, 4 large Ptolomeus, 6 middle 

ditto, 6 fmall ar.d 2 G eek 

ff 1 34 Lyfimachus, Myriaicon, Antiochus Epiphanes, Alex 

ander Mag. Philippus II. Moduli, Cleopatra, and 

14 others rare medals, tertii moduli 

35 Greek towns 35, 3 ferrated, and 4 Roman Egyp 
tian 

--

36 Antiques; 1 a bracelet, gilt, a woman painting a 

&quot; J 

man, 2 dyes for chafing, and 2 great likenefles of 

J 

Charles I. and II. 
-

37 The veni vidi vici medal of Julius Caefar, copper; the 

Judea Capte Titi Yefp. in filver ; a fine medal of 

Antonia, and a Jewifh fheckle, filver 

38 An~Q3iaLn]£dal of St. Paul, revjerfe, St. peterjajtr 

dallion oT&quot;Str-Jaines, z of the. 

oval 

copper-,--arfanTTTrdaLaf&apos;S j^nr-^rniiislthd~Cle : 
meirt-T^r^nrdTiinocefiTXtll. both gilt 

IRISH SILVER COINS. 

Sethric, and a penny of John 

&apos;4°&quot; 

41 

43 

&quot; / 

O &apos;Jt&apos;i 

0&apos; ^4&apos; v 

1 

O ^&apos;V 

5 o &apos;3*6 

/-/ .0 

Two pennies of John, 1 coined at Waterford, the 

other at Dublin 

Penny of Henry III. penny and a half-penny of Ed 

ward I. 

-

Penny of Edward II penny of Edward III. ditto of 

Richard II. and a groat 

--

Henry VIII. 2 half groats, ditto bafe great and half 

groat; Philip and Mary, reverfe. Harp 1557; 
James I. Ihilling, fix-pence and three pence 

B 2 

44 Charles 

0 . 

4 

O 

0 3 

0. 

/• &amp; 

0-/0 

0.2-6 

0-J-0 



56 Sir Wiliiam Petty&apos;s general, provincial and particular 
Maps of each County in Ireland, and the Port Folio 

containing them 

BOOKS. 

OCT A V O, &amp; Infra: 

57 Gilpin&apos;s Beehive of the Romifti Church 

Pallavicino&apos;s 
Celeftial Divorce -Funuchifm difplayed 
Apology 
for Alberoni 

Trial of Anglefey 
Letters of 

Matthews and Leitock 
Conjugal Love 
Health, 

a Poem, together 

58 Inftitutions on Health, and 8 others 
Bright on Me 

lancholy, and 2 Volumes of old Ballads, with copper 

plates 

59 Dugdale on Nobility 
Carter&apos;s Analyfis of Honor--

Finett on Foreign Ambafladors --Archeon upon the 

Courts of Juftice 
Lord Somers&apos;s famous Trad in 
Defence of the Revolution 
60 Galen&apos;s Commentaries on Hippocrates&apos;s Epitome --

Epitome of Galen&apos;s Works -Vander Linden, Celfus, 
and Sir Uil. Hutton&apos;s Treatife on Guiacum, black 

letter, printed in 1539, /caret 
61 Dryden&apos;s Juvenal 

Phillips&apos;s Collettion of Poets -

Howard&apos;s Tabula Remedios 
Sir David Lindfay&apos;s 
Works 

62 Pan-


C 

*4 ] 

6z Pancirollus&apos;s memorable Things loll --Walker&apos;s Hiftory 
of Coins and Medals 
63 Mr. Addifon&apos;s Dialogues on ancient Medals 
His 
Eflay on the Knowledge of Medals 
Urfatus Ex-

planatio Notarunj &amp; Literarum 

64 Suetonius Graevii, with plates-Hulfius&apos;s Roman Coins-

Dr. Patin&apos;s Travels 

Suetonius and Tacitu:, tranllated --Emblemata Ama-

toria 

66 The Statutes of the College of Phyficians 

The Crafts 
and Frauds of Phyfic expofed 
The Reftorative of 

Phyfic to its Sincerity and Perfection 
Freind&apos;s 
Commentaries, and feveral more Pamphlets 

Judgments again!! Whoring 

Hritory of Limerick -

Jennings on Medals 

The compleat Gamefter 
Acetria, and the PurchafePs Pattern 
Sir Francis Brewfter on Trade 

Laurence&apos;s Intereft of 
Ireland --Prior&apos;s Lilts of A fentees from Ire 
land, with feveral on Coin, and the ACts of Settle 

ment 

The Marquis of Clanricarde&apos;s Memoirs 

Caflleha-

ven&apos;s Memoirs, Waterford j 75 j 
The firft Edi 

tion of ditto 1651, with the Earl of Anglefey&apos;s An-
fwer, and O&apos;Conner&apos;s Diflertation on the Irilh Colo 
nies edablifhed in Britain 

^V A R TO. 

Verdegan&apos;s. Antiquities 

-Stanifhuifti Dublieniis de 

Rebus in Hibernia Geftis 

71 Gemme Antiche 
Maffei Macarius de Gemmis, to 

which is bound an Account of the Pulvis Febrifugus 

in 1653 
72 Dr. Patin&apos;s Suetonius 
73 Dr. Arbuthnot&apos;s Tables on Coins, Weights, and Mea-

fures 

74 Folkes&apos;s Tables of Englilh Silver Coins, with Snelling&apos;s 

Plates 

F O L r o. 


t *5 3 


/. {0-0 

&lt;7 • 

/Jf &apos; / 

o f-t 

67 • //-0 

O&apos; /.3-

0-
//&quot; 
&gt; 

7* * 

O&apos; A&apos;* 
O&apos;V 0 

a* (V&apos;0 

iJfl* 

/. /. 0 

{/// 6 

bf*/ 

O&apos; //-&apos; 

Wilkes, and an unica Talus, a medal Infcribed, 

Jlet protefiore Jehova, and a Pope&apos;s indulgence 

12 Reprefentation of Chrift and his pafiion, John the 

Baptill, infcribed inttr naios mulierum non jur-

rexit, three brafs medals in high relief, one in a 
frame, the fubje&amp;s Abraham offering Ifaac, 
Mofes and the burning bufh, and the Wifdom of 

Solomon, an oval of the Y&apos;irgin, a filver crucifix, 

graved, and three Pope&apos;s indulgences 
13 Galienu* 40, and 8 brafs 

-

14 Silver denarii from Nerva to Pertinax, in good prefer-
nation 

---

-

t5 An oval medal alto relievo of Cha. T. and his Queen, 

gilt, another of Cha. I. rev. royal arms, in gar 

ter 
-

16 Another fine medal of Cha. I. rev. London, at urhem 
fol orbem rtd:ens 

-

--

17 Silver medallion of the K. of Pruflia, pralium prope 

Rosbach 1757 

18 A German crown made into a patch box, and an oval 

medal Adam and Eve 

19 A fine medal in high relief, gilt, of Henry the Great, 

and Mary de Medicis upon their nuptials 

20 Medallion of King of Pruifia, rex natura. Geo. II. 
Geo. III. accefiion medal, Q. Mary, auando 


31 

33 

&quot;jLj* 

35 

l &apos;7 i 

ediCt of Naples, ex mariyriis palm&lt;e, 2 grand 

medals 

--

: &apos; 

28 Three molt beautiful German medals, upon victo 

ries 

--

Five fine Flanders medals, with plans of towns, 

Sec. 

• 

-

-

-. 

A fine, oval medal, 1&gt;rafs, gilt, of Maurice, prince of 

Orange, rev. bis arms in garter, a grand oval 

medal, Jilver gilt, of Guftavus Adolphus 
A beautiful filver medal in high relief, Chrillina 

1680 

-

A large medallion of Sigifmund III. filver 

Cha. XT. K. of Sweden 1682, Ulrica, Queen of 

Sweden 1693 

-

A very high finifhed medal upon the eleCE of Ch. VI. 

King of the Romans, Nomen omen amen, ano 
ther fine medal of John SobTefici, rtx. &apos;Viem&apos;a 

J. Geo. III. dux Saxon, a fiege medal, gilt, motto, 

Jchova. &apos;vex&apos;llum meutn, Leopold and J. Sobielki, 

dollar of Chriftina, and another German 

Ch. K. of Sardinia, Auguftus III. Poland Staniflaus, 

two of late K. of Prufiia, Emperor Jofephand 

fon 

i 

-
37 Breda medal 1537, gilt, and very fine, ante fame nut 

ajlu, &lt;vi modofatta &apos;via eft 
38 Ecce Uladiflaum, and John Monteregius, governor 

of Burgundy, and four fine German dollars 

A very large medallion, Fran. Redi, with z fine 

reverfe, copper 
---

The K. of Sardinia, and a very fine refpublica Ge* 

nevenfis Dae. j 749 

--

COINS of SCOTLAND. 

Alex. 1, David 1, Robert 2, and half-penny, Alex. 2, 
Alex. 3, David 2 

From Alex. I. to James V. 14 groats, and hirteen 

fmall 

-

; -
44 Medal of Mary, has the arms of France and 
Scotland conjoined, rev. F.M. in cypher, motto, 

•vicit leo de tribu juda 1560, and two coins of 
Mary 

----

-

45 Mary and. Hen. crown, dated 1566, Exurgat deus 
dilpentur inimici, &apos;very fearce 

-

46 James VI. ha&apos;f crown, two fhillings, fix-pence, and 
threepence^James VI. crown, commonly callei 
£ 

% 

Buchanart 

40 

4 1 

9^43 

3 /. y-id 

5 3. 



c&amp;&apos;O 

1 

O&apos;SZ+&apos;V 

1 

• 0&apos; P 

0-u 

5 

6 J?.7*&lt;? 

6 8.-3-a 

, o-

i /? -V 

• 

&amp; 

c &apos; /&apos; 

&gt; 

12 P 

27 

n.o 
rj&apos; 6 

3 c . &amp; 

i c. y-

1 


[ J» ] 

Buchanan dollar, for this pro me Ji merer in 

me 

(?. o. f 

0 

• 

y , D 47 Corouc/icn medal, and a fine fix pence of 

P &apos; 

^&apos;i&apos;i.iilU&apos; ha)&apos;crown, /hilling. fix-pence, an 

j t ^49 Cha. L ha.. c; u• n &apos; kid cbor, /hilling, fix-pence, 

four &apos;.nee, ihn r-pe* e, two-pence and penny, 

/ 

motto, Chrijio ay Ua rtgno 

ft &apos; % -&amp; 50 Two fix-pence*, four-pence, and three pence, dated 

of Cha. I. 

Cha. I. 

and two-pence 

&apos;43 nd 

3 

0^5 1 Cha. I haif crown, fix-pen*c, and penny, Scotch 

coinage 

-

-

0 y . 

£ 52 Dublin hair~c rrwr -tnd lhilling, called Ormond 

money, and on-&apos;-pence, three-pence, two-pence 
and penny, new coinage 

-

/&apos; /A ^53 E^phant crown, role crown, and a box crown 

Charles II. 

O SJt&apos;vS4 William and Mary, two half crowns, the arms dif 

ferently difpoled, three Newark fhillings, and two 

• 

Maflachufets (hillings, Q. Anne&apos;s /hilling, frelh, 

1707, and fix-pence 1711, filver pattern piece 

f 

for 

Ann&apos;s farthing, Lima /hilling Geo. II. 

and his fix-pence, fix pennies, and two half 

pennies 

O , i/, v 55 Three groats from Alex, to Ja. V. half crown, 

lhilling, fix-pence, three-pence and two-pence, 

Cha. I. half crown, gilt, lhilling and lix-pence, 

ditto 

-

ft,/ft• 6$^T wo half crowns, two fhillings, two fix-pcnces, and 

a three-pence of Cha. II. and 2 ten-penny pieces 
of James II. 

6?. 

ftSl 

an d M. forty-pence piece, ten-pence and five-

pence, K. Will, forty-pence, twenty-pence, ten-

pence, and two fi ve-pences, and Queen Anne&apos;s 

five* pence 

^&apos;^&apos;^58 James I. lhilling, fix-pence, and two-pence, Cha. I. 

ha f crown, lhilling, fix-per^c and two-pence, 

Cha. J. haif crown, rnilling, fix pence, and three 

pence _ 

-; ~&apos; 

II xf 

ft.y, O 59 Ancient Britifh ccpp-r coin, ard 3 Saxon 

-

4 

? 

II 

/&apos;/• C 

/. /&lt; ft 

/4&gt;o 

cV 

60 Edgar and 3 Saxor, t6 pennies from Henry I. to 

Edw. 1. 0 halfpennies, and 4 farthings 

26 

61 Sixteen groats, 4 half groats, and 19 pennies from 

) ft 

Edw. I. to-&apos; Iemy VII. -

39 

62 Thirty two awinit pennies, fcveral of them found in 

Phlhoplgaic Street, three groats, 1 Hen&apos;* VII. 2 

Hen. V II. and 2 half greats, one marked 
T. W. 


44 &lt;s&gt;. 

[ &gt;9 J 

.jf * 

T. W. fliilling and fix-pence, Ed. VI. and two 

fix-pmces of Q^Eliz. 

-

63 Three ihillings and three fix-pences of James I. 

and a remaVkable token for two-pence, Cha. 1. 
two crowns, three half crowns, fix Ihillings, three 
fix pence*, eight two pences, and one half penny 

Irifli pennies of Edw. I. and II. one coined at Water 

ford, the other at Dublin 

65 A penny of Edw. I. ditto, Edw. II. ditto, Edw. III. 

coined in Ireland 

GroatofRich.il. Dublin 

-

-

67 Harp groat of Hen. VIII. three broad faced groats of 

ditto, bale metal 

-

James I. harp fix-pence and three-pence, and fix 

pieces black money 

25 A //&lt; 6. 

2 
&lt;?•/• 

&amp; 

3 0 tfi.c 

1 

/, b 

4 o /• 0 

8 0-3&apos; &amp; 

COPPER. 

ty/ru v&gt;y Q_ Anne&apos;s farthing and halfpenny, &apos;very fine 

/ 

/70 Halfpenny and farthing of Geo. I. fine, and a .half-

&apos; 

1 

penny of George II. with a crucifix enamel-

led 

: 

( A box farthing, containing a quarter guinea of 
George I. 

Jac. II D. G. M. B. F. and H. K. a king&apos;s evil 

piece iiiftead of gold, cujus eft, gilt. Common 

wealth London penny, upper gallery ticket 1684, 
ticket for the King&apos;s private roads 1731, Gou-

gius 1736, an iron die of an half-penny of 

George li. 

• 

; -

2 A /• O 

O ./£&apos; O 

PRINTS, &amp;c. 

A Port Foho ; containing large Metzotintos of the late 
Dauphin and the King of Pruffia, with eleven o* 

triers 

-
-

! 3 

A Vellum Book,-in which is contained 4:1 Prints, Sic. 

large and fmall 

PAMPHLETS. 

75 Low Life between Saturday Night and Monday Morn 
ing 

Betty li eland 

Henry Grace -Mifs 

Biandy 

Two on J. Cajfar -John pouiter, and 
Catalogue of rarities 

76 Fourteen Pamphlets, fbtne Catalogues, ana me public 

Accounts of Ireland, Civil and Military 

books 


t 20 1 

BOOKS; 

OCTAVO &amp;? Infra. 

77 Epiflles of Gildas, who flourifhcd in 1546, the mofl 
ancient Britifh Author 
Efiay on Phyfic in the 
Bible 
78 Bafil Valentine 
Cornelius Agrippa 
Monafticon 
Britannicum, and five others 

Si, V A R i 0. 

79 Portraits of Painters, and Number 1 of Perry&apos;s Englilh 

Medals 

80 Landi Numifmata &amp; Seguini Selefta Numifmata 

81 Oifelii Thefaurus 

FOLIO. 

82 Cave&apos;s Lives of Chrifl and the Apoflles-Cave&apos;s hives 

&quot; 

of the Fathers 

; , 

Begeri Antiquitates 
Perrier&apos;s Antique Statues 

84 Begeri Numifmata --Nicholfon&apos;s Hillorical Library 
Gordon&apos;s Itinerarium 
Nummi Bodleani 

A Series of the Icons of the Englifh Coinage, palled on 

a Royal Folio, collected from the bell Plates and 
Books; to which is annexed, the Saxon and Scot-
tifn Series 

CABINETS, kc. 

88 A curious Moore Man&apos;s fword ahd creese, made at 
Ifpahan, finely tempered, and inlaid with gold 
*9 A ftnall pen and pencil cafe, for ink, filver, with a 

tin cafe, and a deceptive fnufr box, new, with a 

picture of a dutchefs, and a medal glafs 
90 A cabinet, con aining certain natural curiofities 
91 An ebony cabinet, with 15 large drawers, for a Riman 
feries, the ceils lined with green ve&apos; /et, the h. r al id 

key very fine 

92 A mahogany cabinet ; containing 44 ebor^dfiwer*, 
with double leav&apos;d d ors 
93 An oak cabinet, with double leav&apos;d drawers 
94 A large folio book cabinet, with 8 drawers 
95 A l&apos;niail folio bock cabinet 

F ir N I s. 




k 








. 








1 </unit>

























</text>
</tei>